<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Researches on Pestilli Lab</title><link>https://PESTILLILAB.github.io/research/</link><description>Recent content in Researches on Pestilli Lab</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://PESTILLILAB.github.io/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>BD Hubs: Collaborative Proposal: Midwest: Midwest Big Data Hub: Building Communities to Harness the Data Revolution</title><link>https://PESTILLILAB.github.io/research/1916518/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://PESTILLILAB.github.io/research/1916518/</guid><description/></item><item><title>BD Spokes: SPOKE: MIDWEST: Collaborative: Advanced Computational Neuroscience Network (ACNN)</title><link>https://PESTILLILAB.github.io/research/1636893/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://PESTILLILAB.github.io/research/1636893/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Collaborative Proposal: CRCNS US-German Data Sharing Proposal: DataLad - a decentralized system for integrated discovery, management, and publication of digital objects of science</title><link>https://PESTILLILAB.github.io/research/1912270/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://PESTILLILAB.github.io/research/1912270/</guid><description/></item><item><title>DATA NEUROSCIENCE and MACHINE LEARNING</title><link>https://PESTILLILAB.github.io/research/feature_dataneuro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://PESTILLILAB.github.io/research/feature_dataneuro/</guid><description>It has been claimed that data is the new oil. Today, a great potential for impact and a variety of applications exist for psychological science outside the traditional domain. Data about human behavior is collected routinely on cloud platforms around the nation, often for commerce sometimes for good other times for less clear purposes. Indeed, a majority of what is commonly referred to as Data Science can be specified as Psychological Data Science.</description></item><item><title>Example Slide</title><link>https://PESTILLILAB.github.io/research/banner_example/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://PESTILLILAB.github.io/research/banner_example/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Harnessing machine learning and cloud computing to test biological models of the role of white matter in human learning</title><link>https://PESTILLILAB.github.io/research/2004877/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://PESTILLILAB.github.io/research/2004877/</guid><description/></item><item><title>NCS-FO: Connectome mapping algorithms with application to community services for big data neuroscience</title><link>https://PESTILLILAB.github.io/research/1734853/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://PESTILLILAB.github.io/research/1734853/</guid><description/></item><item><title>OPEN NEUROSCIENCE and CLOUD TECHNOLOGY</title><link>https://PESTILLILAB.github.io/research/feature_openneuro_cloud/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://PESTILLILAB.github.io/research/feature_openneuro_cloud/</guid><description>We promote the application of cloud technology to psychological and brain science research. Why use cloud technology in neuroscience? “Isn’t that just for games or business?” Companies like Apple, Microsoft, Google, FaceBook and Amazon among thousands have benefited tremendously by developing products that use cloud services. A cloud service is software that runs for you via a remote computer. Software that does not sit inside a lab in an office building.</description></item><item><title>The Human Visual Pathways and Skilled Reading</title><link>https://PESTILLILAB.github.io/research/1228397/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://PESTILLILAB.github.io/research/1228397/</guid><description/></item><item><title>VISUAL WHITE MATTER and BRAIN NETWORKS</title><link>https://PESTILLILAB.github.io/research/feature_visualwhitematter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://PESTILLILAB.github.io/research/feature_visualwhitematter/</guid><description>Most humans use vision to explore the world. Clarifying how vision works is critical to understanding the brain and making progress towards disease prevention and cure. Visual function requires coordinating the activity of multiple components; the eye, cortical and subcortical brain regions. In the brain, visual signals travel across long-range myelinated axonal pathways that form an extensive network of neurons and brain areas. This myelinated network of neurons and axons is generally referred to as the ‘white matter.</description></item></channel></rss>