<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>pestilli, F[Author]</title>
    <link>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/rss-feed/?feed_id=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&amp;utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;v=2.14.3&amp;ff=20210323133437&amp;fc=20210112114804&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_source=Python Requests</link>
    <description>pestilli, F[Author]: Latest results from PubMed</description>
    <atom:link href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/rss-feed/?feed_id=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&amp;utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;v=2.14.3&amp;ff=20210323133437&amp;fc=20210112114804&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_source=Python Requests" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>PubMed RSS feeds (2.14.3)</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 17:34:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <ttl>120</ttl>
    <item>
      <title>Collegiate athlete brain data for white matter mapping and network neuroscience</title>
      <link>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/33574337/?utm_source=Python Requests&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&amp;fc=20210112114804&amp;ff=20210323133437&amp;v=2.14.3</link>
      <description>We describe a dataset of processed data with associated reproducible preprocessing pipeline collected from two collegiate athlete groups and one non-athlete group. The dataset shares minimally processed diffusion-weighted magnetic resonance imaging (dMRI) data, three models of the diffusion signal in the voxel, full-brain tractograms, segmentation of the major white matter tracts as well as structural connectivity matrices. There is currently a paucity of similar datasets openly shared....</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Sci Data. 2021 Feb 11;8(1):56. doi: 10.1038/s41597-021-00823-z.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">We describe a dataset of processed data with associated reproducible preprocessing pipeline collected from two collegiate athlete groups and one non-athlete group. The dataset shares minimally processed diffusion-weighted magnetic resonance imaging (dMRI) data, three models of the diffusion signal in the voxel, full-brain tractograms, segmentation of the major white matter tracts as well as structural connectivity matrices. There is currently a paucity of similar datasets openly shared. Furthermore, major challenges are associated with collecting this type of data. The data and derivatives shared here can be used as a reference to study the effects of long-term exposure to collegiate athletics, such as the effects of repetitive head impacts. We use advanced anatomical and dMRI data processing methods publicly available as reproducible web services at brainlife.io.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/33574337/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">33574337</a> | PMC:<a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/PMC7878753/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">PMC7878753</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1038/s41597-021-00823-z>10.1038/s41597-021-00823-z</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">pubmed:33574337</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Bradley Caron</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Ricardo Stuck</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Brent McPherson</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Daniel Bullock</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Lindsey Kitchell</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Joshua Faskowitz</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Derek Kellar</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Hu Cheng</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Sharlene Newman</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Nicholas Port</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Franco Pestilli</dc:creator>
      <dc:date>2021-02-12</dc:date>
      <dc:source>Scientific data</dc:source>
      <dc:title>Collegiate athlete brain data for white matter mapping and network neuroscience</dc:title>
      <dc:identifier>pmid:33574337</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>pmc:PMC7878753</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>doi:10.1038/s41597-021-00823-z</dc:identifier>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Spread of COVID-19 Increases With Individual Mobility and Depends on Political Leaning</title>
      <link>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/33564757/?utm_source=Python Requests&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&amp;fc=20210112114804&amp;ff=20210323133437&amp;v=2.14.3</link>
      <description>The implementation of social distancing policies is key to reducing the impact of the current COVID-19 pandemic. However, their effectiveness ultimately depends on human behavior. In the United States, compliance with social distancing policies has widely varied thus far during the pandemic. But what drives such variability? Through six open datasets, including actual human mobility, we estimated the association between mobility and the growth rate of COVID-19 cases across 3,107 U.S. counties,...</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Res Sq. 2021 Feb 4:rs.3.rs-147801. doi: 10.21203/rs.3.rs-147801/v1. Preprint.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">The implementation of social distancing policies is key to reducing the impact of the current COVID-19 pandemic. However, their effectiveness ultimately depends on human behavior. In the United States, compliance with social distancing policies has widely varied thus far during the pandemic. But what drives such variability? Through six open datasets, including actual human mobility, we estimated the association between mobility and the growth rate of COVID-19 cases across 3,107 U.S. counties, generalizing previous reports. In addition, data from the 2016 U.S. presidential election was used to measure how the association between mobility and COVID-19 growth rate differed based on voting patterns. A significant association between political leaning and the COVID-19 growth rate was measured. Our results demonstrate that political orientation may inform models predicting the impact of policies in reducing the spread of COVID-19.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/33564757/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">33564757</a> | PMC:<a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/PMC7872364/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">PMC7872364</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-147801/v1>10.21203/rs.3.rs-147801/v1</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">pubmed:33564757</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Chris Parker</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Jorge Mejia</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Franco Pestilli</dc:creator>
      <dc:date>2021-02-10</dc:date>
      <dc:source>Research square</dc:source>
      <dc:title>The Spread of COVID-19 Increases With Individual Mobility and Depends on Political Leaning</dc:title>
      <dc:identifier>pmid:33564757</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>pmc:PMC7872364</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>doi:10.21203/rs.3.rs-147801/v1</dc:identifier>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The human endogenous attentional control network includes a ventro-temporal cortical node</title>
      <link>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/33452252/?utm_source=Python Requests&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&amp;fc=20210112114804&amp;ff=20210323133437&amp;v=2.14.3</link>
      <description>Endogenous attention is the cognitive function that selects the relevant pieces of sensory information to achieve goals and it is known to be controlled by dorsal fronto-parietal brain areas. Here we expand this notion by identifying a control attention area located in the temporal lobe. By combining a demanding behavioral paradigm with functional neuroimaging and diffusion tractography, we show that like fronto-parietal attentional areas, the human posterior inferotemporal cortex exhibits...</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Nat Commun. 2021 Jan 15;12(1):360. doi: 10.1038/s41467-020-20583-5.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Endogenous attention is the cognitive function that selects the relevant pieces of sensory information to achieve goals and it is known to be controlled by dorsal fronto-parietal brain areas. Here we expand this notion by identifying a control attention area located in the temporal lobe. By combining a demanding behavioral paradigm with functional neuroimaging and diffusion tractography, we show that like fronto-parietal attentional areas, the human posterior inferotemporal cortex exhibits significant attentional modulatory activity. This area is functionally distinct from surrounding cortical areas, and is directly connected to parietal and frontal attentional regions. These results show that attentional control spans three cortical lobes and overarches large distances through fiber pathways that run orthogonally to the dominant anterior-posterior axes of sensory processing, thus suggesting a different organizing principle for cognitive control.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/33452252/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">33452252</a> | PMC:<a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/PMC7810878/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">PMC7810878</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-020-20583-5>10.1038/s41467-020-20583-5</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">pubmed:33452252</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Ilaria Sani</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Heiko Stemmann</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Bradley Caron</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Daniel Bullock</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Torsten Stemmler</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Manfred Fahle</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Franco Pestilli</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Winrich A Freiwald</dc:creator>
      <dc:date>2021-01-16</dc:date>
      <dc:source>Nature communications</dc:source>
      <dc:title>The human endogenous attentional control network includes a ventro-temporal cortical node</dc:title>
      <dc:identifier>pmid:33452252</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>pmc:PMC7810878</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>doi:10.1038/s41467-020-20583-5</dc:identifier>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bundle analytics, a computational framework for investigating the shapes and profiles of brain pathways across populations</title>
      <link>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/33051471/?utm_source=Python Requests&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&amp;fc=20210112114804&amp;ff=20210323133437&amp;v=2.14.3</link>
      <description>Tractography has created new horizons for researchers to study brain connectivity in vivo. However, tractography is an advanced and challenging method that has not been used so far for medical data analysis at a large scale in comparison to other traditional brain imaging methods. This work allows tractography to be used for large scale and high-quality medical analytics. BUndle ANalytics (BUAN) is a fast, robust, and flexible computational framework for real-world tractometric studies. BUAN...</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Sci Rep. 2020 Oct 13;10(1):17149. doi: 10.1038/s41598-020-74054-4.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Tractography has created new horizons for researchers to study brain connectivity in vivo. However, tractography is an advanced and challenging method that has not been used so far for medical data analysis at a large scale in comparison to other traditional brain imaging methods. This work allows tractography to be used for large scale and high-quality medical analytics. BUndle ANalytics (BUAN) is a fast, robust, and flexible computational framework for real-world tractometric studies. BUAN combines tractography and anatomical information to analyze the challenging datasets and identifies significant group differences in specific locations of the white matter bundles. Additionally, BUAN takes the shape of the bundles into consideration for the analysis. BUAN compares the shapes of the bundles using a metric called bundle adjacency which calculates shape similarity between two given bundles. BUAN builds networks of bundle shape similarities that can be paramount for automating quality control. BUAN is freely available in DIPY. Results are presented using publicly available Parkinson's Progression Markers Initiative data.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/33051471/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">33051471</a> | PMC:<a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/PMC7555507/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">PMC7555507</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-020-74054-4>10.1038/s41598-020-74054-4</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">pubmed:33051471</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Bramsh Qamar Chandio</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Shannon Leigh Risacher</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Franco Pestilli</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Daniel Bullock</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Fang-Cheng Yeh</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Serge Koudoro</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Ariel Rokem</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Jaroslaw Harezlak</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Eleftherios Garyfallidis</dc:creator>
      <dc:date>2020-10-14</dc:date>
      <dc:source>Scientific reports</dc:source>
      <dc:title>Bundle analytics, a computational framework for investigating the shapes and profiles of brain pathways across populations</dc:title>
      <dc:identifier>pmid:33051471</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>pmc:PMC7555507</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>doi:10.1038/s41598-020-74054-4</dc:identifier>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Classifyber, a robust streamline-based linear classifier for white matter bundle segmentation</title>
      <link>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32979520/?utm_source=Python Requests&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&amp;fc=20210112114804&amp;ff=20210323133437&amp;v=2.14.3</link>
      <description>Virtual delineation of white matter bundles in the human brain is of paramount importance for multiple applications, such as pre-surgical planning and connectomics. A substantial body of literature is related to methods that automatically segment bundles from diffusion Magnetic Resonance Imaging (dMRI) data indirectly, by exploiting either the idea of connectivity between regions or the geometry of fiber paths obtained with tractography techniques, or, directly, through the information in...</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Neuroimage. 2021 Jan 1;224:117402. doi: 10.1016/j.neuroimage.2020.117402. Epub 2020 Sep 23.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Virtual delineation of white matter bundles in the human brain is of paramount importance for multiple applications, such as pre-surgical planning and connectomics. A substantial body of literature is related to methods that automatically segment bundles from diffusion Magnetic Resonance Imaging (dMRI) data indirectly, by exploiting either the idea of connectivity between regions or the geometry of fiber paths obtained with tractography techniques, or, directly, through the information in volumetric data. Despite the remarkable improvement in automatic segmentation methods over the years, their segmentation quality is not yet satisfactory, especially when dealing with datasets with very diverse characteristics, such as different tracking methods, bundle sizes or data quality. In this work, we propose a novel, supervised streamline-based segmentation method, called Classifyber, which combines information from atlases, connectivity patterns, and the geometry of fiber paths into a simple linear model. With a wide range of experiments on multiple datasets that span from research to clinical domains, we show that Classifyber substantially improves the quality of segmentation as compared to other state-of-the-art methods and, more importantly, that it is robust across very diverse settings. We provide an implementation of the proposed method as open source code, as well as web service.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32979520/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">32979520</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuroimage.2020.117402>10.1016/j.neuroimage.2020.117402</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">pubmed:32979520</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Giulia Bertò</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Daniel Bullock</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Pietro Astolfi</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Soichi Hayashi</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Luca Zigiotto</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Luciano Annicchiarico</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Francesco Corsini</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Alessandro De Benedictis</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Silvio Sarubbo</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Franco Pestilli</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Paolo Avesani</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Emanuele Olivetti</dc:creator>
      <dc:date>2020-09-26</dc:date>
      <dc:source>NeuroImage</dc:source>
      <dc:title>Classifyber, a robust streamline-based linear classifier for white matter bundle segmentation</dc:title>
      <dc:identifier>pmid:32979520</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.neuroimage.2020.117402</dc:identifier>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Open science, communal culture, and women's participation in the movement to improve science</title>
      <link>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32929006/?utm_source=Python Requests&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&amp;fc=20210112114804&amp;ff=20210323133437&amp;v=2.14.3</link>
      <description>Science is undergoing rapid change with the movement to improve science focused largely on reproducibility/replicability and open science practices. This moment of change-in which science turns inward to examine its methods and practices-provides an opportunity to address its historic lack of diversity and noninclusive culture. Through network modeling and semantic analysis, we provide an initial exploration of the structure, cultural frames, and women's participation in the open science and...</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2020 Sep 29;117(39):24154-24164. doi: 10.1073/pnas.1921320117. Epub 2020 Sep 14.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Science is undergoing rapid change with the movement to improve science focused largely on reproducibility/replicability and open science practices. This moment of change-in which science turns inward to examine its methods and practices-provides an opportunity to address its historic lack of diversity and noninclusive culture. Through network modeling and semantic analysis, we provide an initial exploration of the structure, cultural frames, and women's participation in the open science and reproducibility literatures (<i>n</i> = 2,926 articles and conference proceedings). Network analyses suggest that the open science and reproducibility literatures are emerging relatively independently of each other, sharing few common papers or authors. We next examine whether the literatures differentially incorporate collaborative, prosocial ideals that are known to engage members of underrepresented groups more than independent, winner-takes-all approaches. We find that open science has a more connected, collaborative structure than does reproducibility. Semantic analyses of paper abstracts reveal that these literatures have adopted different cultural frames: open science includes more explicitly communal and prosocial language than does reproducibility. Finally, consistent with literature suggesting the diversity benefits of communal and prosocial purposes, we find that women publish more frequently in high-status author positions (first or last) within open science (vs. reproducibility). Furthermore, this finding is further patterned by team size and time. Women are more represented in larger teams within reproducibility, and women's participation is increasing in open science over time and decreasing in reproducibility. We conclude with actionable suggestions for cultivating a more prosocial and diverse culture of science.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32929006/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">32929006</a> | PMC:<a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/PMC7533847/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">PMC7533847</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1921320117>10.1073/pnas.1921320117</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">pubmed:32929006</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Mary C Murphy</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Amanda F Mejia</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Jorge Mejia</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Xiaoran Yan</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Sapna Cheryan</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Nilanjana Dasgupta</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Mesmin Destin</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Stephanie A Fryberg</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Julie A Garcia</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Elizabeth L Haines</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Judith M Harackiewicz</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Alison Ledgerwood</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Corinne A Moss-Racusin</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Lora E Park</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Sylvia P Perry</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Kate A Ratliff</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Aneeta Rattan</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Diana T Sanchez</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Krishna Savani</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Denise Sekaquaptewa</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Jessi L Smith</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Valerie Jones Taylor</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Dustin B Thoman</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Daryl A Wout</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Patricia L Mabry</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Susanne Ressl</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Amanda B Diekman</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Franco Pestilli</dc:creator>
      <dc:date>2020-09-15</dc:date>
      <dc:source>Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America</dc:source>
      <dc:title>Open science, communal culture, and women's participation in the movement to improve science</dc:title>
      <dc:identifier>pmid:32929006</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>pmc:PMC7533847</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>doi:10.1073/pnas.1921320117</dc:identifier>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The visual white matter connecting human area prostriata and the thalamus is retinotopically organized</title>
      <link>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32535840/?utm_source=Python Requests&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&amp;fc=20210112114804&amp;ff=20210323133437&amp;v=2.14.3</link>
      <description>The human visual system is capable of processing visual information from fovea to the far peripheral visual field. Recent fMRI studies have shown a full and detailed retinotopic map in area prostriata, located ventro-dorsally and anterior to the calcarine sulcus along the parieto-occipital sulcus with strong preference for peripheral and wide-field stimulation. Here, we report the anatomical pattern of white matter connections between area prostriata and the thalamus encompassing the lateral...</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Brain Struct Funct. 2020 Jul;225(6):1839-1853. doi: 10.1007/s00429-020-02096-5. Epub 2020 Jun 13.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">The human visual system is capable of processing visual information from fovea to the far peripheral visual field. Recent fMRI studies have shown a full and detailed retinotopic map in area prostriata, located ventro-dorsally and anterior to the calcarine sulcus along the parieto-occipital sulcus with strong preference for peripheral and wide-field stimulation. Here, we report the anatomical pattern of white matter connections between area prostriata and the thalamus encompassing the lateral geniculate nucleus (LGN). To this end, we developed and utilized an automated pipeline comprising a series of Apps that run openly on the cloud computing platform brainlife.io to analyse 139 subjects of the Human Connectome Project (HCP). We observe a continuous and extended bundle of white matter fibers from which two subcomponents can be extracted: one passing ventrally parallel to the optic radiations (OR) and another passing dorsally circumventing the lateral ventricle. Interestingly, the loop travelling dorsally connects the thalamus with the central visual field representation of prostriata located anteriorly, while the other loop travelling more ventrally connects the LGN with the more peripheral visual field representation located posteriorly. We then analyse an additional cohort of 10 HCP subjects using a manual plane extraction method outside brainlife.io to study the relationship between the two extracted white matter subcomponents and eccentricity, myelin and cortical thickness gradients within prostriata. Our results are consistent with a retinotopic segregation recently demonstrated in the OR, connecting the LGN and V1 in humans and reveal for the first time a retinotopic segregation regarding the trajectory of a fiber bundle between the thalamus and an associative visual area.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32535840/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">32535840</a> | PMC:<a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/PMC7321903/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">PMC7321903</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1007/s00429-020-02096-5>10.1007/s00429-020-02096-5</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">pubmed:32535840</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Jan W Kurzawski</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Kyriaki Mikellidou</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Maria Concetta Morrone</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Franco Pestilli</dc:creator>
      <dc:date>2020-06-15</dc:date>
      <dc:source>Brain structure &amp; function</dc:source>
      <dc:title>The visual white matter connecting human area prostriata and the thalamus is retinotopically organized</dc:title>
      <dc:identifier>pmid:32535840</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>pmc:PMC7321903</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>doi:10.1007/s00429-020-02096-5</dc:identifier>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Triple visual hemifield maps in a case of optic chiasm hypoplasia</title>
      <link>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32276070/?utm_source=Python Requests&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&amp;fc=20210112114804&amp;ff=20210323133437&amp;v=2.14.3</link>
      <description>In humans, each hemisphere comprises an overlay of two visuotopic maps of the contralateral visual field, one from each eye. Is the capacity of the visual cortex limited to these two maps or are plastic mechanisms available to host more maps? We determined the cortical organization of the visual field maps in a rare individual with chiasma hypoplasia, where visual cortex plasticity is challenged to accommodate three hemifield maps. Using high-resolution fMRI at 7T and diffusion-weighted MRI at...</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Neuroimage. 2020 Jul 15;215:116822. doi: 10.1016/j.neuroimage.2020.116822. Epub 2020 Apr 8.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">In humans, each hemisphere comprises an overlay of two visuotopic maps of the contralateral visual field, one from each eye. Is the capacity of the visual cortex limited to these two maps or are plastic mechanisms available to host more maps? We determined the cortical organization of the visual field maps in a rare individual with chiasma hypoplasia, where visual cortex plasticity is challenged to accommodate three hemifield maps. Using high-resolution fMRI at 7T and diffusion-weighted MRI at 3T, we found three hemiretinal inputs, instead of the normal two, to converge onto the left hemisphere. fMRI-based population receptive field mapping of the left V1-V3 at 3T revealed three superimposed hemifield representations in the left visual cortex, i.e. two representations of opposing visual hemifields from the left eye and one right hemifield representation from the right eye. We conclude that developmental plasticity including the re-wiring of local intra- and cortico-cortical connections is pivotal to support the coexistence and functioning of three hemifield maps within one hemisphere.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32276070/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">32276070</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuroimage.2020.116822>10.1016/j.neuroimage.2020.116822</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">pubmed:32276070</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2020 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Khazar Ahmadi</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Alessio Fracasso</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Robert J Puzniak</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Andre D Gouws</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Renat Yakupov</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Oliver Speck</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Joern Kaufmann</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Franco Pestilli</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Serge O Dumoulin</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Antony B Morland</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Michael B Hoffmann</dc:creator>
      <dc:date>2020-04-11</dc:date>
      <dc:source>NeuroImage</dc:source>
      <dc:title>Triple visual hemifield maps in a case of optic chiasm hypoplasia</dc:title>
      <dc:identifier>pmid:32276070</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.neuroimage.2020.116822</dc:identifier>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spatial organization of occipital white matter tracts in the common marmoset</title>
      <link>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32253509/?utm_source=Python Requests&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&amp;fc=20210112114804&amp;ff=20210323133437&amp;v=2.14.3</link>
      <description>The primate brain contains a large number of interconnected visual areas, whose spatial organization and intracortical projections show a high level of conservation across species. One fiber pathway of recent interest is the vertical occipital fasciculus (VOF), which is thought to support communication between dorsal and ventral visual areas in the occipital lobe. A recent comparative diffusion MRI (dMRI) study reported that the VOF in the macaque brain bears a similar topology to that of the...</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Brain Struct Funct. 2020 May;225(4):1313-1326. doi: 10.1007/s00429-020-02060-3. Epub 2020 Apr 6.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">The primate brain contains a large number of interconnected visual areas, whose spatial organization and intracortical projections show a high level of conservation across species. One fiber pathway of recent interest is the vertical occipital fasciculus (VOF), which is thought to support communication between dorsal and ventral visual areas in the occipital lobe. A recent comparative diffusion MRI (dMRI) study reported that the VOF in the macaque brain bears a similar topology to that of the human, running superficial and roughly perpendicular to the optic radiation. The present study reports a comparative investigation of the VOF in the common marmoset, a small New World monkey whose lissencephalic brain is approximately tenfold smaller than the macaque and 150-fold smaller than the human. High-resolution ex vivo dMRI of two marmoset brains revealed an occipital white matter structure that closely resembles that of the larger primate species, with one notable difference. Namely, unlike in the macaque and the human, the VOF in the marmoset is spatially fused with other, more anterior vertical tracts, extending anteriorly between the parietal and temporal cortices. We compare several aspects of this continuous structure, which we term the VOF complex (VOF +), and neighboring fasciculi to those of macaques and humans. We hypothesize that the essential topology of the VOF+ is a conserved feature of the posterior cortex in anthropoid primates, with a clearer fragmentation into multiple named fasciculi in larger, more gyrified brains.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32253509/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">32253509</a> | PMC:<a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/PMC7577349/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">PMC7577349</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1007/s00429-020-02060-3>10.1007/s00429-020-02060-3</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">pubmed:32253509</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Takaaki Kaneko</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Hiromasa Takemura</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Franco Pestilli</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Afonso C Silva</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Frank Q Ye</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>David A Leopold</dc:creator>
      <dc:date>2020-04-08</dc:date>
      <dc:source>Brain structure &amp; function</dc:source>
      <dc:title>Spatial organization of occipital white matter tracts in the common marmoset</dc:title>
      <dc:identifier>pmid:32253509</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>pmc:PMC7577349</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>doi:10.1007/s00429-020-02060-3</dc:identifier>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tractostorm: The what, why, and how of tractography dissection reproducibility</title>
      <link>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/31925871/?utm_source=Python Requests&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&amp;fc=20210112114804&amp;ff=20210323133437&amp;v=2.14.3</link>
      <description>Investigative studies of white matter (WM) brain structures using diffusion MRI (dMRI) tractography frequently require manual WM bundle segmentation, often called "virtual dissection." Human errors and personal decisions make these manual segmentations hard to reproduce, which have not yet been quantified by the dMRI community. It is our opinion that if the field of dMRI tractography wants to be taken seriously as a widespread clinical tool, it is imperative to harmonize WM bundle segmentations...</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Hum Brain Mapp. 2020 May;41(7):1859-1874. doi: 10.1002/hbm.24917. Epub 2020 Jan 10.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Investigative studies of white matter (WM) brain structures using diffusion MRI (dMRI) tractography frequently require manual WM bundle segmentation, often called "virtual dissection." Human errors and personal decisions make these manual segmentations hard to reproduce, which have not yet been quantified by the dMRI community. It is our opinion that if the field of dMRI tractography wants to be taken seriously as a widespread clinical tool, it is imperative to harmonize WM bundle segmentations and develop protocols aimed to be used in clinical settings. The EADC-ADNI Harmonized Hippocampal Protocol achieved such standardization through a series of steps that must be reproduced for every WM bundle. This article is an observation of the problematic. A specific bundle segmentation protocol was used in order to provide a real-life example, but the contribution of this article is to discuss the need for reproducibility and standardized protocol, as for any measurement tool. This study required the participation of 11 experts and 13 nonexperts in neuroanatomy and "virtual dissection" across various laboratories and hospitals. Intra-rater agreement (Dice score) was approximately 0.77, while inter-rater was approximately 0.65. The protocol provided to participants was not necessarily optimal, but its design mimics, in essence, what will be required in future protocols. Reporting tractometry results such as average fractional anisotropy, volume or streamline count of a particular bundle without a sufficient reproducibility score could make the analysis and interpretations more difficult. Coordinated efforts by the diffusion MRI tractography community are needed to quantify and account for reproducibility of WM bundle extraction protocols in this era of open and collaborative science.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/31925871/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">31925871</a> | PMC:<a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/PMC7267902/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">PMC7267902</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1002/hbm.24917>10.1002/hbm.24917</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">pubmed:31925871</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Francois Rheault</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Alessandro De Benedictis</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Alessandro Daducci</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Chiara Maffei</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Chantal M W Tax</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>David Romascano</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Eduardo Caverzasi</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Felix C Morency</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Francesco Corrivetti</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Franco Pestilli</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Gabriel Girard</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Guillaume Theaud</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Ilyess Zemmoura</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Janice Hau</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Kelly Glavin</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Kesshi M Jordan</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Kristofer Pomiecko</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Maxime Chamberland</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Muhamed Barakovic</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Nil Goyette</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Philippe Poulin</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Quentin Chenot</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Sandip S Panesar</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Silvio Sarubbo</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Laurent Petit</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Maxime Descoteaux</dc:creator>
      <dc:date>2020-01-12</dc:date>
      <dc:source>Human brain mapping</dc:source>
      <dc:title>Tractostorm: The what, why, and how of tractography dissection reproducibility</dc:title>
      <dc:identifier>pmid:31925871</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>pmc:PMC7267902</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>doi:10.1002/hbm.24917</dc:identifier>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantifying nerve decussation abnormalities in the optic chiasm</title>
      <link>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/31722288/?utm_source=Python Requests&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&amp;fc=20210112114804&amp;ff=20210323133437&amp;v=2.14.3</link>
      <description>CONCLUSIONS: Especially CSD-based tractography provides an efficient approach to detect structural abnormalities in the optic chiasm. The most realistic results were obtained with filtering methods with parameters optimized for the data at hand.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Neuroimage Clin. 2019;24:102055. doi: 10.1016/j.nicl.2019.102055. Epub 2019 Nov 1.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">OBJECTIVE: The human optic chiasm comprises partially crossing optic nerve fibers. Here we used diffusion MRI (dMRI) for the in-vivo identification of the abnormally high proportion of crossing fibers found in the optic chiasm of people with albinism.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">METHODS: In 9 individuals with albinism and 8 controls high-resolution 3T dMRI data was acquired and analyzed with a set of methods for signal modeling [Diffusion Tensor (DT) and Constrained Spherical Deconvolution (CSD)], tractography, and streamline filtering (LiFE, COMMIT, and SIFT2). The number of crossing and non-crossing streamlines and their weights after filtering entered ROC-analyses to compare the discriminative power of the methods based on the area under the curve (AUC). The dMRI results were cross-validated with fMRI estimates of misrouting in a subset of 6 albinotic individuals.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">RESULTS: We detected significant group differences in chiasmal crossing for both unfiltered DT (p = 0.014) and CSD tractograms (p = 0.0009) also reflected by AUC measures (for DT and CSD: 0.61 and 0.75, respectively), underlining the discriminative power of the approach. Estimates of crossing strengths obtained with dMRI and fMRI were significantly correlated for CSD (R<sup>2</sup> = 0.83, p = 0.012). The results show that streamline filtering methods in combination with probabilistic tracking, both optimized for the data at hand, can improve the detection of crossing in the human optic chiasm.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">CONCLUSIONS: Especially CSD-based tractography provides an efficient approach to detect structural abnormalities in the optic chiasm. The most realistic results were obtained with filtering methods with parameters optimized for the data at hand.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">SIGNIFICANCE: Our findings demonstrate a novel anatomy-driven approach for the individualized diagnostics of optic chiasm abnormalities.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/31722288/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">31722288</a> | PMC:<a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/PMC6849426/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">PMC6849426</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nicl.2019.102055>10.1016/j.nicl.2019.102055</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">pubmed:31722288</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2019 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Robert J Puzniak</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Khazar Ahmadi</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Jörn Kaufmann</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Andre Gouws</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Antony B Morland</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Franco Pestilli</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Michael B Hoffmann</dc:creator>
      <dc:date>2019-11-14</dc:date>
      <dc:source>NeuroImage. Clinical</dc:source>
      <dc:title>Quantifying nerve decussation abnormalities in the optic chiasm</dc:title>
      <dc:identifier>pmid:31722288</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>pmc:PMC6849426</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.nicl.2019.102055</dc:identifier>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Open data on industry payments to healthcare providers reveal potential hidden costs to the public</title>
      <link>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/31541096/?utm_source=Python Requests&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&amp;fc=20210112114804&amp;ff=20210323133437&amp;v=2.14.3</link>
      <description>Healthcare industry players make payments to medical providers for non-research expenses. While these payments may pose conflicts of interest, their relationship with overall healthcare costs remains largely unknown. In this study, we linked Open Payments data on providers' industry payments with Medicare data on healthcare costs. We investigated 374,766 providers' industry payments and healthcare costs. We demonstrate that providers receiving higher amounts of industry payments tend to bill...</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Nat Commun. 2019 Sep 20;10(1):4314. doi: 10.1038/s41467-019-12317-z.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Healthcare industry players make payments to medical providers for non-research expenses. While these payments may pose conflicts of interest, their relationship with overall healthcare costs remains largely unknown. In this study, we linked Open Payments data on providers' industry payments with Medicare data on healthcare costs. We investigated 374,766 providers' industry payments and healthcare costs. We demonstrate that providers receiving higher amounts of industry payments tend to bill higher drug and medical costs. Specifically, we find that a 10% increase in industry payments is associated with 1.3% higher medical and 1.8% higher drug costs. For a typical provider, for example, a 10% or $25 increase in annual industry payments would be associated with approximately $1,100 higher medical costs and $100 higher drug costs. Furthermore, the association between payments and healthcare costs varies markedly across states and correlates with political leaning, being stronger in more conservative states.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/31541096/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">31541096</a> | PMC:<a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/PMC6754508/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">PMC6754508</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-019-12317-z>10.1038/s41467-019-12317-z</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">pubmed:31541096</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Jorge Mejia</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Amanda Mejia</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Franco Pestilli</dc:creator>
      <dc:date>2019-09-22</dc:date>
      <dc:source>Nature communications</dc:source>
      <dc:title>Open data on industry payments to healthcare providers reveal potential hidden costs to the public</dc:title>
      <dc:identifier>pmid:31541096</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>pmc:PMC6754508</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>doi:10.1038/s41467-019-12317-z</dc:identifier>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Methods for analysis of brain connectivity: An IFCN-sponsored review</title>
      <link>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/31401492/?utm_source=Python Requests&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&amp;fc=20210112114804&amp;ff=20210323133437&amp;v=2.14.3</link>
      <description>The goal of this paper is to examine existing methods to study the "Human Brain Connectome" with a specific focus on the neurophysiological ones. In recent years, a new approach has been developed to evaluate the anatomical and functional organization of the human brain: the aim of this promising multimodality effort is to identify and classify neuronal networks with a number of neurobiologically meaningful and easily computable measures to create its connectome. By defining anatomical and...</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Clin Neurophysiol. 2019 Oct;130(10):1833-1858. doi: 10.1016/j.clinph.2019.06.006. Epub 2019 Jul 2.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">The goal of this paper is to examine existing methods to study the "Human Brain Connectome" with a specific focus on the neurophysiological ones. In recent years, a new approach has been developed to evaluate the anatomical and functional organization of the human brain: the aim of this promising multimodality effort is to identify and classify neuronal networks with a number of neurobiologically meaningful and easily computable measures to create its connectome. By defining anatomical and functional connections of brain regions on the same map through an integrated approach, comprising both modern neurophysiological and neuroimaging (i.e. flow/metabolic) brain-mapping techniques, network analysis becomes a powerful tool for exploring structural-functional connectivity mechanisms and for revealing etiological relationships that link connectivity abnormalities to neuropsychiatric disorders. Following a recent IFCN-endorsed meeting, a panel of international experts was selected to produce this current state-of-art document, which covers the available knowledge on anatomical and functional connectivity, including the most commonly used structural and functional MRI, EEG, MEG and non-invasive brain stimulation techniques and measures of local and global brain connectivity.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/31401492/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">31401492</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.clinph.2019.06.006>10.1016/j.clinph.2019.06.006</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">pubmed:31401492</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>P M Rossini</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>R Di Iorio</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>M Bentivoglio</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>G Bertini</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>F Ferreri</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>C Gerloff</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>R J Ilmoniemi</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>F Miraglia</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>M A Nitsche</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>F Pestilli</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>M Rosanova</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Y Shirota</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>C Tesoriero</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Y Ugawa</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>F Vecchio</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>U Ziemann</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>M Hallett</dc:creator>
      <dc:date>2019-08-12</dc:date>
      <dc:source>Clinical neurophysiology : official journal of the International Federation of Clinical Neurophysiology</dc:source>
      <dc:title>Methods for analysis of brain connectivity: An IFCN-sponsored review</dc:title>
      <dc:identifier>pmid:31401492</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.clinph.2019.06.006</dc:identifier>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ReAl-LiFE: Accelerating the Discovery of Individualized Brain Connectomes on GPUs</title>
      <link>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/31355051/?utm_source=Python Requests&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&amp;fc=20210112114804&amp;ff=20210323133437&amp;v=2.14.3</link>
      <description>Diffusion imaging and tractography enable mapping structural connections in the human brain, in-vivo. Linear Fascicle Evaluation (LiFE) is a state-of-the-art approach for pruning spurious connections in the estimated structural connectome, by optimizing its fit to the measured diffusion data. Yet, LiFE imposes heavy demands on computing time, precluding its use in analyses of large connectome databases. Here, we introduce a GPU-based implementation of LiFE that achieves 50-100x speedups over...</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Proc Conf AAAI Artif Intell. 2019 Jun 14;33(1):630-638. doi: 10.1609/aaai.v33i01.3301630. Epub 2019 Jul 23.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Diffusion imaging and tractography enable mapping structural connections in the human brain, <i>in-vivo</i>. Linear Fascicle Evaluation (LiFE) is a state-of-the-art approach for pruning spurious connections in the estimated structural connectome, by optimizing its fit to the measured diffusion data. Yet, LiFE imposes heavy demands on computing time, precluding its use in analyses of large connectome databases. Here, we introduce a GPU-based implementation of LiFE that achieves 50-100x speedups over conventional CPU-based implementations for connectome sizes of up to several million fibers. Briefly, the algorithm accelerates generalized matrix multiplications on a compressed tensor through efficient GPU kernels, while ensuring favorable memory access patterns. Leveraging these speedups, we advance LiFE's algorithm by imposing a regularization constraint on estimated fiber weights during connectome pruning. Our regularized, accelerated, LiFE algorithm ("ReAl-LiFE") estimates sparser connectomes that also provide more accurate fits to the underlying diffusion signal. We demonstrate the utility of our approach by classifying pathological signatures of structural connectivity in patients with Alzheimer's Disease (AD). We estimated million fiber whole-brain connectomes, followed by pruning with ReAl-LiFE, for 90 individuals (45 AD patients and 45 healthy controls). Linear classifiers, based on support vector machines, achieved over 80% accuracy in classifying AD patients from healthy controls based on their ReAl-LiFE pruned structural connectomes alone. Moreover, classification based on the ReAl-LiFE pruned connectome outperformed both the unpruned connectome, as well as the LiFE pruned connectome, in terms of accuracy. We propose our GPU-accelerated approach as a widely relevant tool for non-negative least squares optimization, across many domains.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/31355051/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">31355051</a> | PMC:<a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/PMC6660316/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">PMC6660316</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1609/aaai.v33i01.3301630>10.1609/aaai.v33i01.3301630</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">pubmed:31355051</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Sawan Kumar</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Varsha Sreenivasan</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Partha Talukdar</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Franco Pestilli</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Devarajan Sridharan</dc:creator>
      <dc:date>2019-07-30</dc:date>
      <dc:source>Proceedings of the ... AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence. AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence</dc:source>
      <dc:title>ReAl-LiFE: Accelerating the Discovery of Individualized Brain Connectomes on GPUs</dc:title>
      <dc:identifier>pmid:31355051</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>pmc:PMC6660316</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>doi:10.1609/aaai.v33i01.3301630</dc:identifier>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Associative white matter connecting the dorsal and ventral posterior human cortex</title>
      <link>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/31342157/?utm_source=Python Requests&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&amp;fc=20210112114804&amp;ff=20210323133437&amp;v=2.14.3</link>
      <description>Historically, the primary focus of studies of human white matter tracts has been on large tracts that connect anterior-to-posterior cortical regions. These include the superior longitudinal fasciculus (SLF), the inferior longitudinal fasciculus (ILF), and the inferior fronto-occipital fasciculus (IFOF). Recently, more refined and well-understood tractography methods have facilitated the characterization of several tracts in the posterior of the human brain that connect dorsal-to-ventral cortical...</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Brain Struct Funct. 2019 Nov;224(8):2631-2660. doi: 10.1007/s00429-019-01907-8. Epub 2019 Jul 24.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Historically, the primary focus of studies of human white matter tracts has been on large tracts that connect anterior-to-posterior cortical regions. These include the superior longitudinal fasciculus (SLF), the inferior longitudinal fasciculus (ILF), and the inferior fronto-occipital fasciculus (IFOF). Recently, more refined and well-understood tractography methods have facilitated the characterization of several tracts in the posterior of the human brain that connect dorsal-to-ventral cortical regions. These include the vertical occipital fasciculus (VOF), the posterior arcuate fasciculus (pArc), the temporo-parietal connection (TP-SPL), and the middle longitudinal fasciculus (MdLF). The addition of these dorso-ventral connective tracts to our standard picture of white matter architecture results in a more complicated pattern of white matter connectivity than previously considered. Dorso-ventral connective tracts may play a role in transferring information from superior horizontal tracts, such as the SLF, to inferior horizontal tracts, such as the IFOF and ILF. We present a full anatomical delineation of these major dorso-ventral connective white matter tracts (the VOF, pArc, TP-SPL, and MdLF). We show their spatial layout and cortical termination mappings in relation to the more established horizontal tracts (SLF, IFOF, ILF, and Arc) and consider standard values for quantitative features associated with the aforementioned tracts. We hope to facilitate further study on these tracts and their relations. To this end, we also share links to automated code that segments these tracts, thereby providing a standard approach to obtaining these tracts for subsequent analysis. We developed open source software to allow reproducible segmentation of the tracts: https://github.com/brainlife/Vertical_Tracts . Finally, we make the segmentation method available as an open cloud service on the data and analyses sharing platform brainlife.io. Investigators will be able to access these services and upload their data to segment these tracts.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/31342157/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">31342157</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1007/s00429-019-01907-8>10.1007/s00429-019-01907-8</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">pubmed:31342157</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Daniel Bullock</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Hiromasa Takemura</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Cesar F Caiafa</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Lindsey Kitchell</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Brent McPherson</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Bradley Caron</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Franco Pestilli</dc:creator>
      <dc:date>2019-07-26</dc:date>
      <dc:source>Brain structure &amp; function</dc:source>
      <dc:title>Associative white matter connecting the dorsal and ventral posterior human cortex</dc:title>
      <dc:identifier>pmid:31342157</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>doi:10.1007/s00429-019-01907-8</dc:identifier>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The open diffusion data derivatives, brain data upcycling via integrated publishing of derivatives and reproducible open cloud services</title>
      <link>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/31123325/?utm_source=Python Requests&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&amp;fc=20210112114804&amp;ff=20210323133437&amp;v=2.14.3</link>
      <description>We describe the Open Diffusion Data Derivatives (O3D) repository: an integrated collection of preserved brain data derivatives and processing pipelines, published together using a single digital-object-identifier. The data derivatives were generated using modern diffusion-weighted magnetic resonance imaging data (dMRI) with diverse properties of resolution and signal-to-noise ratio. In addition to the data, we publish all processing pipelines (also referred to as open cloud services). The...</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Sci Data. 2019 May 23;6(1):69. doi: 10.1038/s41597-019-0073-y.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">We describe the Open Diffusion Data Derivatives (O3D) repository: an integrated collection of preserved brain data derivatives and processing pipelines, published together using a single digital-object-identifier. The data derivatives were generated using modern diffusion-weighted magnetic resonance imaging data (dMRI) with diverse properties of resolution and signal-to-noise ratio. In addition to the data, we publish all processing pipelines (also referred to as open cloud services). The pipelines utilize modern methods for neuroimaging data processing (diffusion-signal modelling, fiber tracking, tractography evaluation, white matter segmentation, and structural connectome construction). The O3D open services can allow cognitive and clinical neuroscientists to run the connectome mapping algorithms on new, user-uploaded, data. Open source code implementing all O3D services is also provided to allow computational and computer scientists to reuse and extend the processing methods. Publishing both data-derivatives and integrated processing pipeline promotes practices for scientific reproducibility and data upcycling by providing open access to the research assets for utilization by multiple scientific communities.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/31123325/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">31123325</a> | PMC:<a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/PMC6533280/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">PMC6533280</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1038/s41597-019-0073-y>10.1038/s41597-019-0073-y</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">pubmed:31123325</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2019 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Paolo Avesani</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Brent McPherson</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Soichi Hayashi</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Cesar F Caiafa</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Robert Henschel</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Eleftherios Garyfallidis</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Lindsey Kitchell</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Daniel Bullock</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Andrew Patterson</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Emanuele Olivetti</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Olaf Sporns</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Andrew J Saykin</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Lei Wang</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Ivo Dinov</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>David Hancock</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Bradley Caron</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Yiming Qian</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Franco Pestilli</dc:creator>
      <dc:date>2019-05-25</dc:date>
      <dc:source>Scientific data</dc:source>
      <dc:title>The open diffusion data derivatives, brain data upcycling via integrated publishing of derivatives and reproducible open cloud services</dc:title>
      <dc:identifier>pmid:31123325</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>pmc:PMC6533280</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>doi:10.1038/s41597-019-0073-y</dc:identifier>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Functionally defined white matter of the macaque monkey brain reveals a dorso-ventral attention network</title>
      <link>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/30601116/?utm_source=Python Requests&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&amp;fc=20210112114804&amp;ff=20210323133437&amp;v=2.14.3</link>
      <description>Classical studies of attention have identified areas of parietal and frontal cortex as sources of attentional control. Recently, a ventral region in the macaque temporal cortex, the posterior infero-temporal dorsal area PITd, has been suggested as a third attentional control area. This raises the question of whether and how spatially distant areas coordinate a joint focus of attention. Here we tested the hypothesis that parieto-frontal attention areas and PITd are directly interconnected. By...</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Elife. 2019 Jan 2;8:e40520. doi: 10.7554/eLife.40520.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Classical studies of attention have identified areas of parietal and frontal cortex as sources of attentional control. Recently, a ventral region in the macaque temporal cortex, the posterior infero-temporal dorsal area PITd, has been suggested as a third attentional control area. This raises the question of whether and how spatially distant areas coordinate a joint focus of attention. Here we tested the hypothesis that parieto-frontal attention areas and PITd are directly interconnected. By combining functional MRI with ex-vivo high-resolution diffusion MRI, we found that PITd and dorsal attention areas are all directly connected through three specific fascicles. These results ascribe a new function, the communication of attention signals, to two known fiber-bundles, highlight the importance of vertical interactions across the two visual streams, and imply that the control of endogenous attention, hitherto thought to reside in macaque dorsal cortical areas, is exerted by a dorso-ventral network.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/30601116/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">30601116</a> | PMC:<a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/PMC6345568/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">PMC6345568</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.7554/eLife.40520>10.7554/eLife.40520</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">pubmed:30601116</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Ilaria Sani</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Brent C McPherson</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Heiko Stemmann</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Franco Pestilli</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Winrich A Freiwald</dc:creator>
      <dc:date>2019-01-03</dc:date>
      <dc:source>eLife</dc:source>
      <dc:title>Functionally defined white matter of the macaque monkey brain reveals a dorso-ventral attention network</dc:title>
      <dc:identifier>pmid:30601116</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>pmc:PMC6345568</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>doi:10.7554/eLife.40520</dc:identifier>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparative neuroanatomy: Integrating classic and modern methods to understand association fibers connecting dorsal and ventral visual cortex</title>
      <link>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/30389574/?utm_source=Python Requests&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&amp;fc=20210112114804&amp;ff=20210323133437&amp;v=2.14.3</link>
      <description>Comparative neuroanatomy studies improve understanding of brain structure and function and provide insight regarding brain development, evolution, and also what features of the brain are uniquely human. With modern methods such as diffusion MRI (dMRI) and quantitative MRI (qMRI), we are able to measure structural features of the brain with the same methods across human and non-human primates. In this review article, we discuss how recent dMRI measurements of vertical occipital connections in...</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Neurosci Res. 2019 Sep;146:1-12. doi: 10.1016/j.neures.2018.10.011. Epub 2018 Oct 30.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Comparative neuroanatomy studies improve understanding of brain structure and function and provide insight regarding brain development, evolution, and also what features of the brain are uniquely human. With modern methods such as diffusion MRI (dMRI) and quantitative MRI (qMRI), we are able to measure structural features of the brain with the same methods across human and non-human primates. In this review article, we discuss how recent dMRI measurements of vertical occipital connections in humans and macaques can be compared with previous findings from invasive anatomical studies that examined connectivity, including relatively forgotten classic strychnine neuronography studies. We then review recent progress in understanding the neuroanatomy of vertical connections within the occipitotemporal cortex by combining modern quantitative MRI and classical histological measurements in human and macaque. Finally, we a) discuss current limitations of dMRI and tractography and b) consider potential paths for future investigations using dMRI and tractography for comparative neuroanatomical studies of white matter tracts between species. While we focus on vertical association connections in visual cortex in the present paper, this same approach can be applied to other white matter tracts. Similar efforts are likely to continue to advance our understanding of the neuroanatomical features of the brain that are shared across species, as well as to distinguish the features that are uniquely human.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/30389574/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">30389574</a> | PMC:<a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/PMC6491271/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">PMC6491271</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neures.2018.10.011>10.1016/j.neures.2018.10.011</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">pubmed:30389574</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Hiromasa Takemura</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Franco Pestilli</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Kevin S Weiner</dc:creator>
      <dc:date>2018-11-04</dc:date>
      <dc:source>Neuroscience research</dc:source>
      <dc:title>Comparative neuroanatomy: Integrating classic and modern methods to understand association fibers connecting dorsal and ventral visual cortex</dc:title>
      <dc:identifier>pmid:30389574</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>pmc:PMC6491271</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.neures.2018.10.011</dc:identifier>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Age-related macular degeneration affects the optic radiation white matter projecting to locations of retinal damage</title>
      <link>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/29951918/?utm_source=Python Requests&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&amp;fc=20210112114804&amp;ff=20210323133437&amp;v=2.14.3</link>
      <description>We investigated the impact of age-related macular degeneration (AMD) on visual acuity and the visual white matter. We combined an adaptive cortical atlas and diffusion-weighted magnetic resonance imaging (dMRI) and tractography to separate optic radiation (OR) projections to different retinal eccentricities in human primary visual cortex. We exploited the known anatomical organization of the OR and clinically relevant data to segment the OR into three primary components projecting to fovea, mid-...</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Brain Struct Funct. 2018 Nov;223(8):3889-3900. doi: 10.1007/s00429-018-1702-5. Epub 2018 Jun 27.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">We investigated the impact of age-related macular degeneration (AMD) on visual acuity and the visual white matter. We combined an adaptive cortical atlas and diffusion-weighted magnetic resonance imaging (dMRI) and tractography to separate optic radiation (OR) projections to different retinal eccentricities in human primary visual cortex. We exploited the known anatomical organization of the OR and clinically relevant data to segment the OR into three primary components projecting to fovea, mid- and far-periphery. We measured white matter tissue properties-fractional anisotropy, linearity, planarity, sphericity-along the aforementioned three components of the optic radiation to compare AMD patients and controls. We found differences in white matter properties specific to OR white matter fascicles projecting to primary visual cortex locations corresponding to the location of retinal damage (fovea). Additionally, we show that the magnitude of white matter properties in AMD patients' correlates with visual acuity. In sum, we demonstrate a specific relation between visual loss, anatomical location of retinal damage and white matter damage in AMD patients. Importantly, we demonstrate that these changes are so profound that can be detected using magnetic resonance imaging data with clinical resolution. The conserved mapping between retinal and white matter damage suggests that retinal neurodegeneration might be a primary cause of white matter degeneration in AMD patients. The results highlight the impact of eye disease on brain tissue, a process that may become an important target to monitor during the course of treatment.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/29951918/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">29951918</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1007/s00429-018-1702-5>10.1007/s00429-018-1702-5</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">pubmed:29951918</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2018 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Shoyo Yoshimine</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Shumpei Ogawa</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Hiroshi Horiguchi</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Masahiko Terao</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Atsushi Miyazaki</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Kenji Matsumoto</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Hiroshi Tsuneoka</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Tadashi Nakano</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Yoichiro Masuda</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Franco Pestilli</dc:creator>
      <dc:date>2018-06-29</dc:date>
      <dc:source>Brain structure &amp; function</dc:source>
      <dc:title>Age-related macular degeneration affects the optic radiation white matter projecting to locations of retinal damage</dc:title>
      <dc:identifier>pmid:29951918</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>doi:10.1007/s00429-018-1702-5</dc:identifier>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Human white matter and knowledge representation</title>
      <link>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/29698391/?utm_source=Python Requests&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&amp;fc=20210112114804&amp;ff=20210323133437&amp;v=2.14.3</link>
      <description>Understanding how knowledge is represented in the human brain is a fundamental challenge in neuroscience. To date, most of the work on this topic has focused on knowledge representation in cortical areas and debated whether knowledge is represented in a distributed or localized fashion. Fang and colleagues provide evidence that brain connections and the white matter supporting such connections might play a significant role. The work opens new avenues of investigation, breaking through...</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">PLoS Biol. 2018 Apr 26;16(4):e2005758. doi: 10.1371/journal.pbio.2005758. eCollection 2018 Apr.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Understanding how knowledge is represented in the human brain is a fundamental challenge in neuroscience. To date, most of the work on this topic has focused on knowledge representation in cortical areas and debated whether knowledge is represented in a distributed or localized fashion. Fang and colleagues provide evidence that brain connections and the white matter supporting such connections might play a significant role. The work opens new avenues of investigation, breaking through disciplinary boundaries across network neuroscience, computational neuroscience, cognitive science, and classical lesion studies.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/29698391/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">29698391</a> | PMC:<a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/PMC5940236/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">PMC5940236</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pbio.2005758>10.1371/journal.pbio.2005758</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">pubmed:29698391</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Franco Pestilli</dc:creator>
      <dc:date>2018-04-27</dc:date>
      <dc:source>PLoS biology</dc:source>
      <dc:title>Human white matter and knowledge representation</dc:title>
      <dc:identifier>pmid:29698391</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>pmc:PMC5940236</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>doi:10.1371/journal.pbio.2005758</dc:identifier>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparing fMRI activation during smooth pursuit eye movements among contact sport athletes, non-contact sport athletes, and non-athletes</title>
      <link>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/29541575/?utm_source=Python Requests&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&amp;fc=20210112114804&amp;ff=20210323133437&amp;v=2.14.3</link>
      <description>CONCLUSION: Greater cerebellar activity among football players while performing an oculomotor task could indicate that they are working harder to compensate for some subtle, long-term subconcussive deficits. Alternatively, top athletes in a sport requiring high visual motor skill could have more of their cerebellum and FEF devoted to oculomotor task performance regardless of subconcussive history. Overall, these results provide little firm support for an effect of accumulated subconcussion...</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Neuroimage Clin. 2018 Jan 31;18:413-424. doi: 10.1016/j.nicl.2018.01.025. eCollection 2018.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">OBJECTIVES: Though sub-concussive impacts are common during contact sports, there is little consensus whether repeat blows affect brain function. Using a "lifetime exposure" rather than acute exposure approach, we examined oculomotor performance and brain activation among collegiate football players and two control groups. Our analysis examined whether there are group differences in eye movement behavioral performance and in brain activation during smooth pursuit.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">METHODS: Data from 21 off-season Division I football "starters" were compared with a) 19 collegiate cross-country runners, and b) 11 non-athlete college students who were SES matched to the football player group (total <i>N</i> = 51). Visual smooth pursuit was performed while undergoing fMRI imaging via a 3 Tesla scanner. Smooth pursuit eye movements to three stimulus difficulty levels were measured with regard to RMS error, gain, and lag.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">RESULTS: No meaningful differences were found for any of the standard analyses used to assess smooth pursuit eye movements. For fMRI, greater activation was seen in the oculomotor region of the cerebellar vermis and areas of the FEF for football players as compared to either control group, who did not differ on any measure.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">CONCLUSION: Greater cerebellar activity among football players while performing an oculomotor task could indicate that they are working harder to compensate for some subtle, long-term subconcussive deficits. Alternatively, top athletes in a sport requiring high visual motor skill could have more of their cerebellum and FEF devoted to oculomotor task performance regardless of subconcussive history. Overall, these results provide little firm support for an effect of accumulated subconcussion exposure on brain function.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/29541575/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">29541575</a> | PMC:<a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/PMC5849867/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">PMC5849867</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nicl.2018.01.025>10.1016/j.nicl.2018.01.025</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">pubmed:29541575</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Derek Kellar</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Sharlene Newman</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Franco Pestilli</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Hu Cheng</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Nicholas L Port</dc:creator>
      <dc:date>2018-03-16</dc:date>
      <dc:source>NeuroImage. Clinical</dc:source>
      <dc:title>Comparing fMRI activation during smooth pursuit eye movements among contact sport athletes, non-contact sport athletes, and non-athletes</dc:title>
      <dc:identifier>pmid:29541575</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>pmc:PMC5849867</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.nicl.2018.01.025</dc:identifier>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Framework for shape analysis of white matter fiber bundles</title>
      <link>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/29203454/?utm_source=Python Requests&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&amp;fc=20210112114804&amp;ff=20210323133437&amp;v=2.14.3</link>
      <description>Diffusion imaging coupled with tractography algorithms allows researchers to image human white matter fiber bundles in-vivo. These bundles are three-dimensional structures with shapes that change over time during the course of development as well as in pathologic states. While most studies on white matter variability focus on analysis of tissue properties estimated from the diffusion data, e.g. fractional anisotropy, the shape variability of white matter fiber bundle is much less explored. In...</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Neuroimage. 2018 Feb 15;167:466-477. doi: 10.1016/j.neuroimage.2017.11.052. Epub 2017 Dec 2.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Diffusion imaging coupled with tractography algorithms allows researchers to image human white matter fiber bundles in-vivo. These bundles are three-dimensional structures with shapes that change over time during the course of development as well as in pathologic states. While most studies on white matter variability focus on analysis of tissue properties estimated from the diffusion data, e.g. fractional anisotropy, the shape variability of white matter fiber bundle is much less explored. In this paper, we present a set of tools for shape analysis of white matter fiber bundles, namely: (1) a concise geometric model of bundle shapes; (2) a method for bundle registration between subjects; (3) a method for deformation estimation. Our framework is useful for analysis of shape variability in white matter fiber bundles. We demonstrate our framework by applying our methods on two datasets: one consisting of data for 6 normal adults and another consisting of data for 38 normal children of age 11 days to 8.5 years. We suggest a robust and reproducible method to measure changes in the shape of white matter fiber bundles. We demonstrate how this method can be used to create a model to assess age-dependent changes in the shape of specific fiber bundles. We derive such models for an ensemble of white matter fiber bundles on our pediatric dataset and show that our results agree with normative human head and brain growth data. Creating these models for a large pediatric longitudinal dataset may improve understanding of both normal development and pathologic states and propose novel parameters for the examination of the pediatric brain.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/29203454/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">29203454</a> | PMC:<a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/PMC5845796/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">PMC5845796</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuroimage.2017.11.052>10.1016/j.neuroimage.2017.11.052</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">pubmed:29203454</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2017 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Tanya Glozman</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Lisa Bruckert</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Franco Pestilli</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Derek W Yecies</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Leonidas J Guibas</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Kristen W Yeom</dc:creator>
      <dc:date>2017-12-06</dc:date>
      <dc:source>NeuroImage</dc:source>
      <dc:title>Framework for shape analysis of white matter fiber bundles</dc:title>
      <dc:identifier>pmid:29203454</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>pmc:PMC5845796</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.neuroimage.2017.11.052</dc:identifier>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multidimensional encoding of brain connectomes</title>
      <link>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/28904382/?utm_source=Python Requests&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&amp;fc=20210112114804&amp;ff=20210323133437&amp;v=2.14.3</link>
      <description>The ability to map brain networks in living individuals is fundamental in efforts to chart the relation between human behavior, health and disease. Advances in network neuroscience may benefit from developing new frameworks for mapping brain connectomes. We present a framework to encode structural brain connectomes and diffusion-weighted magnetic resonance (dMRI) data using multidimensional arrays. The framework integrates the relation between connectome nodes, edges, white matter fascicles and...</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Sci Rep. 2017 Sep 13;7(1):11491. doi: 10.1038/s41598-017-09250-w.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">The ability to map brain networks in living individuals is fundamental in efforts to chart the relation between human behavior, health and disease. Advances in network neuroscience may benefit from developing new frameworks for mapping brain connectomes. We present a framework to encode structural brain connectomes and diffusion-weighted magnetic resonance (dMRI) data using multidimensional arrays. The framework integrates the relation between connectome nodes, edges, white matter fascicles and diffusion data. We demonstrate the utility of the framework for in vivo white matter mapping and anatomical computing by evaluating 1,490 connectomes, thirteen tractography methods, and three data sets. The framework dramatically reduces storage requirements for connectome evaluation methods, with up to 40x compression factors. Evaluation of multiple, diverse datasets demonstrates the importance of spatial resolution in dMRI. We measured large increases in connectome resolution as function of data spatial resolution (up to 52%). Moreover, we demonstrate that the framework allows performing anatomical manipulations on white matter tracts for statistical inference and to study the white matter geometrical organization. Finally, we provide open-source software implementing the method and data to reproduce the results.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/28904382/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">28904382</a> | PMC:<a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/PMC5597641/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">PMC5597641</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-017-09250-w>10.1038/s41598-017-09250-w</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">pubmed:28904382</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2017 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Cesar F Caiafa</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Franco Pestilli</dc:creator>
      <dc:date>2017-09-15</dc:date>
      <dc:source>Scientific reports</dc:source>
      <dc:title>Multidimensional encoding of brain connectomes</dc:title>
      <dc:identifier>pmid:28904382</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>pmc:PMC5597641</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>doi:10.1038/s41598-017-09250-w</dc:identifier>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Face percept formation in human ventral temporal cortex</title>
      <link>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/28814631/?utm_source=Python Requests&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&amp;fc=20210112114804&amp;ff=20210323133437&amp;v=2.14.3</link>
      <description>Loci in ventral temporal cortex are selectively active during viewing of faces and other objects, but it remains unclear whether these areas represent accumulation of simple visual information or processing of intact percept. We measured broadband electrocorticographic changes from implanted electrodes on the ventral temporal brain surface while showing patients noise-degraded images of faces and houses. In a subset of posterior fusiform gyrus face-selective regions, cortical activity decreased...</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">J Neurophysiol. 2017 Nov 1;118(5):2614-2627. doi: 10.1152/jn.00113.2017. Epub 2017 Aug 16.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Loci in ventral temporal cortex are selectively active during viewing of faces and other objects, but it remains unclear whether these areas represent accumulation of simple visual information or processing of intact percept. We measured broadband electrocorticographic changes from implanted electrodes on the ventral temporal brain surface while showing patients noise-degraded images of faces and houses. In a subset of posterior fusiform gyrus face-selective regions, cortical activity decreased parametrically with noise increase, until the perceptual threshold was surpassed. At noise levels higher than the perceptual threshold, and for house stimuli, activity remained at baseline. We propose that this convergence of proportional and thresholded response may identify active areas where face percepts are extracted from simple visual features. These loci exist within a topological structure of face percept formation in the human ventral visual stream, preceded by category-nonselective activity in pericalcarine early visual areas and in concert with all-or-nothing activity in postperceptual subregions of the ventral temporal lobe. This topological organization suggests a physiological basis for the anatomy of face perception, explaining different perceptual deficits following temporal lobe injury.<b>NEW &amp; NOTEWORTHY</b> Philosophers have puzzled for millennia about how humans build abstract conceptual objects (house/face/tool) from the simple features of the world they see around them (line/patch/lighting). Understanding the biological foundation of this process requires detailed knowledge of the spatial-temporal characteristics of cerebral cortex. By examining the physiology of the human temporal lobe via implanted electrodes while showing subjects noise-degraded images, we find that face percept formation happens in specific subregions within known face-processing areas.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/28814631/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">28814631</a> | PMC:<a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/PMC5668462/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">PMC5668462</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1152/jn.00113.2017>10.1152/jn.00113.2017</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">pubmed:28814631</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2017 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Kai J Miller</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Dora Hermes</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Franco Pestilli</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Gagan S Wig</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Jeffrey G Ojemann</dc:creator>
      <dc:date>2017-08-18</dc:date>
      <dc:source>Journal of neurophysiology</dc:source>
      <dc:title>Face percept formation in human ventral temporal cortex</dc:title>
      <dc:identifier>pmid:28814631</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>pmc:PMC5668462</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>doi:10.1152/jn.00113.2017</dc:identifier>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DTI measures identify mild and moderate TBI cases among patients with complex health problems: A receiver operating characteristic analysis of U.S. veterans</title>
      <link>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/28725550/?utm_source=Python Requests&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&amp;fc=20210112114804&amp;ff=20210323133437&amp;v=2.14.3</link>
      <description>Standard MRI methods are often inadequate for identifying mild traumatic brain injury (TBI). Advances in diffusion tensor imaging now provide potential biomarkers of TBI among white matter fascicles (tracts). However, it is still unclear which tracts are most pertinent to TBI diagnosis. This study ranked fiber tracts on their ability to discriminate patients with and without TBI. We acquired diffusion tensor imaging data from military veterans admitted to a polytrauma clinic (Overall n = 109;...</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Neuroimage Clin. 2017 Jun 24;16:1-16. doi: 10.1016/j.nicl.2017.06.031. eCollection 2017.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Standard MRI methods are often inadequate for identifying mild traumatic brain injury (TBI). Advances in diffusion tensor imaging now provide potential biomarkers of TBI among white matter fascicles (tracts). However, it is still unclear which tracts are most pertinent to TBI diagnosis. This study ranked fiber tracts on their ability to discriminate patients with and without TBI. We acquired diffusion tensor imaging data from military veterans admitted to a polytrauma clinic (Overall <i>n</i> = 109; Age: <i>M</i> = 47.2, <i>SD</i> = 11.3; Male: 88%; TBI: 67%). TBI diagnosis was based on self-report and neurological examination. Fiber tractography analysis produced 20 fiber tracts per patient. Each tract yielded four clinically relevant measures (fractional anisotropy, mean diffusivity, radial diffusivity, and axial diffusivity). We applied receiver operating characteristic (ROC) analyses to identify the most diagnostic tract for each measure. The analyses produced an optimal cutpoint for each tract. We then used kappa coefficients to rate the agreement of each cutpoint with the neurologist's diagnosis. The tract with the highest kappa was most diagnostic. As a check on the ROC results, we performed a stepwise logistic regression on each measure using all 20 tracts as predictors. We also bootstrapped the ROC analyses to compute the 95% confidence intervals for sensitivity, specificity, and the highest kappa coefficients. The ROC analyses identified two fiber tracts as most diagnostic of TBI: the left cingulum (LCG) and the left inferior fronto-occipital fasciculus (LIF). Like ROC, logistic regression identified LCG as most predictive for the FA measure but identified the right anterior thalamic tract (RAT) for the MD, RD, and AD measures. These findings are potentially relevant to the development of TBI biomarkers. Our methods also demonstrate how ROC analysis may be used to identify clinically relevant variables in the TBI population.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/28725550/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">28725550</a> | PMC:<a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/PMC5503837/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">PMC5503837</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nicl.2017.06.031>10.1016/j.nicl.2017.06.031</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">pubmed:28725550</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Keith L Main</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Salil Soman</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Franco Pestilli</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Ansgar Furst</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Art Noda</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Beatriz Hernandez</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Jennifer Kong</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Jauhtai Cheng</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Jennifer K Fairchild</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Joy Taylor</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Jerome Yesavage</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>J Wesson Ashford</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Helena Kraemer</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Maheen M Adamson</dc:creator>
      <dc:date>2017-07-21</dc:date>
      <dc:source>NeuroImage. Clinical</dc:source>
      <dc:title>DTI measures identify mild and moderate TBI cases among patients with complex health problems: A receiver operating characteristic analysis of U.S. veterans</dc:title>
      <dc:identifier>pmid:28725550</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>pmc:PMC5503837</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.nicl.2017.06.031</dc:identifier>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Occipital White Matter Tracts in Human and Macaque</title>
      <link>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/28369290/?utm_source=Python Requests&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&amp;fc=20210112114804&amp;ff=20210323133437&amp;v=2.14.3</link>
      <description>We compare several major white-matter tracts in human and macaque occipital lobe using diffusion magnetic resonance imaging. The comparison suggests similarities but also significant differences in the tracts. There are several apparently homologous tracts in the 2 species, including the vertical occipital fasciculus (VOF), optic radiation, forceps major, and inferior longitudinal fasciculus (ILF). There is one large human tract, the inferior fronto-occipital fasciculus, with no corresponding...</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Cereb Cortex. 2017 Jun 1;27(6):3346-3359. doi: 10.1093/cercor/bhx070.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">We compare several major white-matter tracts in human and macaque occipital lobe using diffusion magnetic resonance imaging. The comparison suggests similarities but also significant differences in the tracts. There are several apparently homologous tracts in the 2 species, including the vertical occipital fasciculus (VOF), optic radiation, forceps major, and inferior longitudinal fasciculus (ILF). There is one large human tract, the inferior fronto-occipital fasciculus, with no corresponding fasciculus in macaque. We could identify the macaque VOF (mVOF), which has been little studied. Its position is consistent with classical invasive anatomical studies by Wernicke. VOF homology is supported by similarity of the endpoints in V3A and ventral V4 across species. The mVOF fibers intertwine with the dorsal segment of the ILF, but the human VOF appears to be lateral to the ILF. These similarities and differences between the occipital lobe tracts will be useful in establishing which circuitry in the macaque can serve as an accurate model for human visual cortex.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/28369290/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">28369290</a> | PMC:<a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/PMC5890896/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">PMC5890896</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1093/cercor/bhx070>10.1093/cercor/bhx070</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">pubmed:28369290</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Hiromasa Takemura</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Franco Pestilli</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Kevin S Weiner</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Georgios A Keliris</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Sofia M Landi</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Julia Sliwa</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Frank Q Ye</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Michael A Barnett</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>David A Leopold</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Winrich A Freiwald</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Nikos K Logothetis</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Brian A Wandell</dc:creator>
      <dc:date>2017-04-04</dc:date>
      <dc:source>Cerebral cortex (New York, N.Y. : 1991)</dc:source>
      <dc:title>Occipital White Matter Tracts in Human and Macaque</dc:title>
      <dc:identifier>pmid:28369290</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>pmc:PMC5890896</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>doi:10.1093/cercor/bhx070</dc:identifier>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The visual white matter: The application of diffusion MRI and fiber tractography to vision science</title>
      <link>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/28196374/?utm_source=Python Requests&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&amp;fc=20210112114804&amp;ff=20210323133437&amp;v=2.14.3</link>
      <description>Visual neuroscience has traditionally focused much of its attention on understanding the response properties of single neurons or neuronal ensembles. The visual white matter and the long-range neuronal connections it supports are fundamental in establishing such neuronal response properties and visual function. This review article provides an introduction to measurements and methods to study the human visual white matter using diffusion MRI. These methods allow us to measure the microstructural...</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">J Vis. 2017 Feb 1;17(2):4. doi: 10.1167/17.2.4.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Visual neuroscience has traditionally focused much of its attention on understanding the response properties of single neurons or neuronal ensembles. The visual white matter and the long-range neuronal connections it supports are fundamental in establishing such neuronal response properties and visual function. This review article provides an introduction to measurements and methods to study the human visual white matter using diffusion MRI. These methods allow us to measure the microstructural and macrostructural properties of the white matter in living human individuals; they allow us to trace long-range connections between neurons in different parts of the visual system and to measure the biophysical properties of these connections. We also review a range of findings from recent studies on connections between different visual field maps, the effects of visual impairment on the white matter, and the properties underlying networks that process visual information supporting visual face recognition. Finally, we discuss a few promising directions for future studies. These include new methods for analysis of MRI data, open datasets that are becoming available to study brain connectivity and white matter properties, and open source software for the analysis of these data.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/28196374/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">28196374</a> | PMC:<a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/PMC5317208/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">PMC5317208</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1167/17.2.4>10.1167/17.2.4</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">pubmed:28196374</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Ariel Rokem</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Hiromasa Takemura</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Andrew S Bock</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>K Suzanne Scherf</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Marlene Behrmann</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Brian A Wandell</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Ione Fine</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Holly Bridge</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Franco Pestilli</dc:creator>
      <dc:date>2017-02-15</dc:date>
      <dc:source>Journal of vision</dc:source>
      <dc:title>The visual white matter: The application of diffusion MRI and fiber tractography to vision science</dc:title>
      <dc:identifier>pmid:28196374</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>pmc:PMC5317208</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>doi:10.1167/17.2.4</dc:identifier>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shape-Attributes of Brain Structures as Biomarkers for Alzheimer's Disease</title>
      <link>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/27911322/?utm_source=Python Requests&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&amp;fc=20210112114804&amp;ff=20210323133437&amp;v=2.14.3</link>
      <description>We describe a fully automatic framework for classification of two types of dementia based on the differences in the shape of brain structures. We consider Alzheimer's disease (AD), mild cognitive impairment of individuals who converted to AD within 18 months (MCIc), and normal controls (NC). Our approach uses statistical learning and a feature space consisting of projection-based shape descriptors, allowing for canonical representation of brain regions. Our framework automatically identifies the...</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">J Alzheimers Dis. 2017;56(1):287-295. doi: 10.3233/JAD-160900.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">We describe a fully automatic framework for classification of two types of dementia based on the differences in the shape of brain structures. We consider Alzheimer's disease (AD), mild cognitive impairment of individuals who converted to AD within 18 months (MCIc), and normal controls (NC). Our approach uses statistical learning and a feature space consisting of projection-based shape descriptors, allowing for canonical representation of brain regions. Our framework automatically identifies the structures most affected by the disease. We evaluate our results by comparing to other methods using a standardized data set of 375 adults available from the Alzheimer's Disease Neuroimaging Initiative (ADNI). Our framework is sensitive to identifying the onset of Alzheimer's disease, achieving up to 88.13% accuracy in classifying MCIc versus NC, outperforming previous methods.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/27911322/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">27911322</a> | PMC:<a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/PMC5240557/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">PMC5240557</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.3233/JAD-160900>10.3233/JAD-160900</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">pubmed:27911322</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2016 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Tanya Glozman</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Justin Solomon</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Franco Pestilli</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Leonidas Guibas</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Alzheimer’s Disease Neuroimaging Initiative</dc:creator>
      <dc:date>2016-12-03</dc:date>
      <dc:source>Journal of Alzheimer's disease : JAD</dc:source>
      <dc:title>Shape-Attributes of Brain Structures as Biomarkers for Alzheimer's Disease</dc:title>
      <dc:identifier>pmid:27911322</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>pmc:PMC5240557</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>doi:10.3233/JAD-160900</dc:identifier>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>White Matter Diffusion of Major Fiber Tracts Implicated in Autism Spectrum Disorder</title>
      <link>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/27555361/?utm_source=Python Requests&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&amp;fc=20210112114804&amp;ff=20210323133437&amp;v=2.14.3</link>
      <description>Autism spectrum disorder (ASD) is a neurodevelopmental disorder found to have widespread alterations in the function and synchrony of brain regions. These differences may underlie alterations in microstructural organization, such as in white matter pathways. To investigate the diffusion of major white matter tracts, the current study examined multiple indices of white matter diffusion in 42 children and adults with ASD and 44 typically developing (TD) age- and IQ-matched peers using diffusion...</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Brain Connect. 2016 Nov;6(9):691-699. doi: 10.1089/brain.2016.0442. Epub 2016 Sep 30.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Autism spectrum disorder (ASD) is a neurodevelopmental disorder found to have widespread alterations in the function and synchrony of brain regions. These differences may underlie alterations in microstructural organization, such as in white matter pathways. To investigate the diffusion of major white matter tracts, the current study examined multiple indices of white matter diffusion in 42 children and adults with ASD and 44 typically developing (TD) age- and IQ-matched peers using diffusion tensor imaging. Diffusivity measures were compared between groups for the following tracts: bilateral cingulum bundle, corpus callosum, inferior longitudinal fasciculus, superior longitudinal fasciculus, and uncinate fasciculus. Results indicate a significant reduction in fractional anisotropy (FA) for the left superior longitudinal fasciculus (LSLF) in ASD children and adults compared with TD peers. A significant increase in radial diffusivity for ASD participants was also found in the same cluster along the LSLF. In addition, a significant positive correlation emerged for all subjects between FA for the LSLF and age, with FA increasing with age. These findings point to a significant alteration in long-distance white matter connectivity in children and adults with ASD, potentially underscoring the relationship between alterations in white matter diffusion and the ASD phenotype. These results also suggest that the white matter alterations in autism may be subtle and related to the developmental trajectory.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/27555361/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">27555361</a> | PMC:<a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/PMC5105348/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">PMC5105348</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1089/brain.2016.0442>10.1089/brain.2016.0442</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">pubmed:27555361</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Lauren E Libero</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Wesley K Burge</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Hrishikesh D Deshpande</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Franco Pestilli</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Rajesh K Kana</dc:creator>
      <dc:date>2016-08-25</dc:date>
      <dc:source>Brain connectivity</dc:source>
      <dc:title>White Matter Diffusion of Major Fiber Tracts Implicated in Autism Spectrum Disorder</dc:title>
      <dc:identifier>pmid:27555361</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>pmc:PMC5105348</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>doi:10.1089/brain.2016.0442</dc:identifier>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ensemble Tractography</title>
      <link>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/26845558/?utm_source=Python Requests&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&amp;fc=20210112114804&amp;ff=20210323133437&amp;v=2.14.3</link>
      <description>Tractography uses diffusion MRI to estimate the trajectory and cortical projection zones of white matter fascicles in the living human brain. There are many different tractography algorithms and each requires the user to set several parameters, such as curvature threshold. Choosing a single algorithm with specific parameters poses two challenges. First, different algorithms and parameter values produce different results. Second, the optimal choice of algorithm and parameter value may differ...</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">PLoS Comput Biol. 2016 Feb 4;12(2):e1004692. doi: 10.1371/journal.pcbi.1004692. eCollection 2016 Feb.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Tractography uses diffusion MRI to estimate the trajectory and cortical projection zones of white matter fascicles in the living human brain. There are many different tractography algorithms and each requires the user to set several parameters, such as curvature threshold. Choosing a single algorithm with specific parameters poses two challenges. First, different algorithms and parameter values produce different results. Second, the optimal choice of algorithm and parameter value may differ between different white matter regions or different fascicles, subjects, and acquisition parameters. We propose using ensemble methods to reduce algorithm and parameter dependencies. To do so we separate the processes of fascicle generation and evaluation. Specifically, we analyze the value of creating optimized connectomes by systematically combining candidate streamlines from an ensemble of algorithms (deterministic and probabilistic) and systematically varying parameters (curvature and stopping criterion). The ensemble approach leads to optimized connectomes that provide better cross-validated prediction error of the diffusion MRI data than optimized connectomes generated using a single-algorithm or parameter set. Furthermore, the ensemble approach produces connectomes that contain both short- and long-range fascicles, whereas single-parameter connectomes are biased towards one or the other. In summary, a systematic ensemble tractography approach can produce connectomes that are superior to standard single parameter estimates both for predicting the diffusion measurements and estimating white matter fascicles. </p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/26845558/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">26845558</a> | PMC:<a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/PMC4742469/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">PMC4742469</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pcbi.1004692>10.1371/journal.pcbi.1004692</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">pubmed:26845558</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2016 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Hiromasa Takemura</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Cesar F Caiafa</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Brian A Wandell</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Franco Pestilli</dc:creator>
      <dc:date>2016-02-05</dc:date>
      <dc:source>PLoS computational biology</dc:source>
      <dc:title>Ensemble Tractography</dc:title>
      <dc:identifier>pmid:26845558</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>pmc:PMC4742469</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>doi:10.1371/journal.pcbi.1004692</dc:identifier>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>White-Matter Tract Connecting Anterior Insula to Nucleus Accumbens Correlates with Reduced Preference for Positively Skewed Gambles</title>
      <link>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/26748088/?utm_source=Python Requests&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&amp;fc=20210112114804&amp;ff=20210323133437&amp;v=2.14.3</link>
      <description>Individuals sometimes show inconsistent risk preferences, including excessive attraction to gambles featuring small chances of winning large amounts (called "positively skewed" gambles). While functional neuroimaging research indicates that nucleus accumbens (NAcc) and anterior insula (AIns) activity inversely predict risky choice, structural connections between these regions have not been described in humans. By combining diffusion-weighted MRI with tractography, we identified the anatomical...</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Neuron. 2016 Jan 6;89(1):63-9. doi: 10.1016/j.neuron.2015.12.015.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Individuals sometimes show inconsistent risk preferences, including excessive attraction to gambles featuring small chances of winning large amounts (called "positively skewed" gambles). While functional neuroimaging research indicates that nucleus accumbens (NAcc) and anterior insula (AIns) activity inversely predict risky choice, structural connections between these regions have not been described in humans. By combining diffusion-weighted MRI with tractography, we identified the anatomical trajectory of white-matter tracts projecting from the AIns to the NAcc and statistically validated these tracts using Linear Fascicle Evaluation (LiFE) and virtual lesions. Coherence of the right AIns-NAcc tract correlated with reduced preferences for positively skewed gambles. Further, diminished NAcc activity during gamble presentation mediated the association between tract structure and choice. These results identify an unreported tract connecting the AIns to the NAcc in humans and support the notion that structural connections can alter behavior by influencing brain activity as individuals weigh uncertain gains against uncertain losses. </p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/26748088/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">26748088</a> | PMC:<a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/PMC4720154/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">PMC4720154</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2015.12.015>10.1016/j.neuron.2015.12.015</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">pubmed:26748088</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2016 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Josiah K Leong</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Franco Pestilli</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Charlene C Wu</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Gregory R Samanez-Larkin</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Brian Knutson</dc:creator>
      <dc:date>2016-01-10</dc:date>
      <dc:source>Neuron</dc:source>
      <dc:title>White-Matter Tract Connecting Anterior Insula to Nucleus Accumbens Correlates with Reduced Preference for Positively Skewed Gambles</dc:title>
      <dc:identifier>pmid:26748088</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>pmc:PMC4720154</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.neuron.2015.12.015</dc:identifier>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Human blindsight is mediated by an intact geniculo-extrastriate pathway</title>
      <link>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/26485034/?utm_source=Python Requests&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&amp;fc=20210112114804&amp;ff=20210323133437&amp;v=2.14.3</link>
      <description>Although damage to the primary visual cortex (V1) causes hemianopia, many patients retain some residual vision; known as blindsight. We show that blindsight may be facilitated by an intact white-matter pathway between the lateral geniculate nucleus and motion area hMT+. Visual psychophysics, diffusion-weighted magnetic resonance imaging and fibre tractography were applied in 17 patients with V1 damage acquired during adulthood and 9 age-matched controls. Individuals with V1 damage were...</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Elife. 2015 Oct 20;4:e08935. doi: 10.7554/eLife.08935.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Although damage to the primary visual cortex (V1) causes hemianopia, many patients retain some residual vision; known as blindsight. We show that blindsight may be facilitated by an intact white-matter pathway between the lateral geniculate nucleus and motion area hMT+. Visual psychophysics, diffusion-weighted magnetic resonance imaging and fibre tractography were applied in 17 patients with V1 damage acquired during adulthood and 9 age-matched controls. Individuals with V1 damage were subdivided into blindsight positive (preserved residual vision) and negative (no residual vision) according to psychophysical performance. All blindsight positive individuals showed intact geniculo-hMT+ pathways, while this pathway was significantly impaired or not measurable in blindsight negative individuals. Two white matter pathways previously implicated in blindsight: (i) superior colliculus to hMT+ and (ii) between hMT+ in each hemisphere were not consistently present in blindsight positive cases. Understanding the visual pathways crucial for residual vision may direct future rehabilitation strategies for hemianopia patients. </p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/26485034/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">26485034</a> | PMC:<a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/PMC4641435/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">PMC4641435</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.7554/eLife.08935>10.7554/eLife.08935</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">pubmed:26485034</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2015 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Sara Ajina</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Franco Pestilli</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Ariel Rokem</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Christopher Kennard</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Holly Bridge</dc:creator>
      <dc:date>2015-10-21</dc:date>
      <dc:source>eLife</dc:source>
      <dc:title>Human blindsight is mediated by an intact geniculo-extrastriate pathway</dc:title>
      <dc:identifier>pmid:26485034</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>pmc:PMC4641435</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>doi:10.7554/eLife.08935</dc:identifier>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Correction: Evaluating the Accuracy of Diffusion MRI Models in White Matter</title>
      <link>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/26394229/?utm_source=Python Requests&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&amp;fc=20210112114804&amp;ff=20210323133437&amp;v=2.14.3</link>
      <description>No abstract</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">PLoS One. 2015 Sep 22;10(9):e0139150. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0139150. eCollection 2015.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/26394229/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">26394229</a> | PMC:<a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/PMC4579137/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">PMC4579137</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0139150>10.1371/journal.pone.0139150</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">pubmed:26394229</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2015 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Ariel Rokem</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Jason D Yeatman</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Franco Pestilli</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Kendrick N Kay</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Aviv Mezer</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Stefan van der Walt</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Brian A Wandell</dc:creator>
      <dc:date>2015-09-23</dc:date>
      <dc:source>PloS one</dc:source>
      <dc:title>Correction: Evaluating the Accuracy of Diffusion MRI Models in White Matter</dc:title>
      <dc:identifier>pmid:26394229</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>pmc:PMC4579137</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0139150</dc:identifier>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-portraits of the brain: cognitive science, data visualization, and communicating brain structure and function</title>
      <link>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/26187032/?utm_source=Python Requests&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&amp;fc=20210112114804&amp;ff=20210323133437&amp;v=2.14.3</link>
      <description>With several large-scale human brain projects currently underway and a range of neuroimaging techniques growing in availability to researchers, the amount and diversity of data relevant for understanding the human brain is increasing rapidly. A complete understanding of the brain must incorporate information about 3D neural location, activity, timing, and task. Data mining, high-performance computing, and visualization can serve as tools that augment human intellect; however, the resulting...</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Trends Cogn Sci. 2015 Aug;19(8):462-74. doi: 10.1016/j.tics.2015.05.012. Epub 2015 Jul 15.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">With several large-scale human brain projects currently underway and a range of neuroimaging techniques growing in availability to researchers, the amount and diversity of data relevant for understanding the human brain is increasing rapidly. A complete understanding of the brain must incorporate information about 3D neural location, activity, timing, and task. Data mining, high-performance computing, and visualization can serve as tools that augment human intellect; however, the resulting visualizations must take into account human abilities and limitations to be effective tools for exploration and communication. In this feature review, we discuss key challenges and opportunities that arise when leveraging the sophisticated perceptual and conceptual processing of the human brain to help researchers understand brain structure, function, and behavior. </p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/26187032/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">26187032</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tics.2015.05.012>10.1016/j.tics.2015.05.012</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">pubmed:26187032</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2015 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Robert L Goldstone</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Franco Pestilli</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Katy Börner</dc:creator>
      <dc:date>2015-07-19</dc:date>
      <dc:source>Trends in cognitive sciences</dc:source>
      <dc:title>Self-portraits of the brain: cognitive science, data visualization, and communicating brain structure and function</dc:title>
      <dc:identifier>pmid:26187032</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.tics.2015.05.012</dc:identifier>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Test-retest measurements and digital validation for in vivo neuroscience</title>
      <link>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/25977807/?utm_source=Python Requests&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&amp;fc=20210112114804&amp;ff=20210323133437&amp;v=2.14.3</link>
      <description>No abstract</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Sci Data. 2015 Jan 20;2:140057. doi: 10.1038/sdata.2014.57. eCollection 2015.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/25977807/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">25977807</a> | PMC:<a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/PMC4412151/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">PMC4412151</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1038/sdata.2014.57>10.1038/sdata.2014.57</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">pubmed:25977807</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2015 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Franco Pestilli</dc:creator>
      <dc:date>2015-05-16</dc:date>
      <dc:source>Scientific data</dc:source>
      <dc:title>Test-retest measurements and digital validation for in vivo neuroscience</dc:title>
      <dc:identifier>pmid:25977807</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>pmc:PMC4412151</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>doi:10.1038/sdata.2014.57</dc:identifier>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating the accuracy of diffusion MRI models in white matter</title>
      <link>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/25879933/?utm_source=Python Requests&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&amp;fc=20210112114804&amp;ff=20210323133437&amp;v=2.14.3</link>
      <description>Models of diffusion MRI within a voxel are useful for making inferences about the properties of the tissue and inferring fiber orientation distribution used by tractography algorithms. A useful model must fit the data accurately. However, evaluations of model-accuracy of commonly used models have not been published before. Here, we evaluate model-accuracy of the two main classes of diffusion MRI models. The diffusion tensor model (DTM) summarizes diffusion as a 3-dimensional Gaussian...</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">PLoS One. 2015 Apr 16;10(4):e0123272. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0123272. eCollection 2015.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Models of diffusion MRI within a voxel are useful for making inferences about the properties of the tissue and inferring fiber orientation distribution used by tractography algorithms. A useful model must fit the data accurately. However, evaluations of model-accuracy of commonly used models have not been published before. Here, we evaluate model-accuracy of the two main classes of diffusion MRI models. The diffusion tensor model (DTM) summarizes diffusion as a 3-dimensional Gaussian distribution. Sparse fascicle models (SFM) summarize the signal as a sum of signals originating from a collection of fascicles oriented in different directions. We use cross-validation to assess model-accuracy at different gradient amplitudes (b-values) throughout the white matter. Specifically, we fit each model to all the white matter voxels in one data set and then use the model to predict a second, independent data set. This is the first evaluation of model-accuracy of these models. In most of the white matter the DTM predicts the data more accurately than test-retest reliability; SFM model-accuracy is higher than test-retest reliability and also higher than the DTM model-accuracy, particularly for measurements with (a) a b-value above 1000 in locations containing fiber crossings, and (b) in the regions of the brain surrounding the optic radiations. The SFM also has better parameter-validity: it more accurately estimates the fiber orientation distribution function (fODF) in each voxel, which is useful for fiber tracking. </p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/25879933/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">25879933</a> | PMC:<a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/PMC4400066/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">PMC4400066</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0123272>10.1371/journal.pone.0123272</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">pubmed:25879933</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2015 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Ariel Rokem</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Jason D Yeatman</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Franco Pestilli</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Kendrick N Kay</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Aviv Mezer</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Stefan van der Walt</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Brian A Wandell</dc:creator>
      <dc:date>2015-04-17</dc:date>
      <dc:source>PloS one</dc:source>
      <dc:title>Evaluating the accuracy of diffusion MRI models in white matter</dc:title>
      <dc:identifier>pmid:25879933</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>pmc:PMC4400066</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0123272</dc:identifier>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Major Human White Matter Pathway Between Dorsal and Ventral Visual Cortex</title>
      <link>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/25828567/?utm_source=Python Requests&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&amp;fc=20210112114804&amp;ff=20210323133437&amp;v=2.14.3</link>
      <description>Human visual cortex comprises many visual field maps organized into clusters. A standard organization separates visual maps into 2 distinct clusters within ventral and dorsal cortex. We combined fMRI, diffusion MRI, and fiber tractography to identify a major white matter pathway, the vertical occipital fasciculus (VOF), connecting maps within the dorsal and ventral visual cortex. We use a model-based method to assess the statistical evidence supporting several aspects of the VOF wiring pattern....</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Cereb Cortex. 2016 May;26(5):2205-2214. doi: 10.1093/cercor/bhv064. Epub 2015 Mar 31.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Human visual cortex comprises many visual field maps organized into clusters. A standard organization separates visual maps into 2 distinct clusters within ventral and dorsal cortex. We combined fMRI, diffusion MRI, and fiber tractography to identify a major white matter pathway, the vertical occipital fasciculus (VOF), connecting maps within the dorsal and ventral visual cortex. We use a model-based method to assess the statistical evidence supporting several aspects of the VOF wiring pattern. There is strong evidence supporting the hypothesis that dorsal and ventral visual maps communicate through the VOF. The cortical projection zones of the VOF suggest that human ventral (hV4/VO-1) and dorsal (V3A/B) maps exchange substantial information. The VOF appears to be crucial for transmitting signals between regions that encode object properties including form, identity, and color and regions that map spatial information. </p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/25828567/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">25828567</a> | PMC:<a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/PMC4830295/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">PMC4830295</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1093/cercor/bhv064>10.1093/cercor/bhv064</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">pubmed:25828567</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2015 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Hiromasa Takemura</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Ariel Rokem</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Jonathan Winawer</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Jason D Yeatman</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Brian A Wandell</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Franco Pestilli</dc:creator>
      <dc:date>2015-04-02</dc:date>
      <dc:source>Cerebral cortex (New York, N.Y. : 1991)</dc:source>
      <dc:title>A Major Human White Matter Pathway Between Dorsal and Ventral Visual Cortex</dc:title>
      <dc:identifier>pmid:25828567</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>pmc:PMC4830295</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>doi:10.1093/cercor/bhv064</dc:identifier>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deconvolution of High Dimensional Mixtures via Boosting, with Application to Diffusion-Weighted MRI of Human Brain</title>
      <link>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/25684972/?utm_source=Python Requests&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&amp;fc=20210112114804&amp;ff=20210323133437&amp;v=2.14.3</link>
      <description>Diffusion-weighted magnetic resonance imaging (DWI) and fiber tractography are the only methods to measure the structure of the white matter in the living human brain. The diffusion signal has been modelled as the combined contribution from many individual fascicles of nerve fibers passing through each location in the white matter. Typically, this is done via basis pursuit, but estimation of the exact directions is limited due to discretization [1, 2]. The difficulties inherent in modeling DWI...</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Adv Neural Inf Process Syst. 2014;27:2699-2707.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Diffusion-weighted magnetic resonance imaging (DWI) and fiber tractography are the only methods to measure the structure of the white matter in the living human brain. The diffusion signal has been modelled as the combined contribution from many individual fascicles of nerve fibers passing through each location in the white matter. Typically, this is done via <i>basis pursuit</i>, but estimation of the exact directions is limited due to discretization [1, 2]. The difficulties inherent in modeling DWI data are shared by many other problems involving fitting non-parametric mixture models. Ekanadaham et al. [3] proposed an approach, <i>continuous basis pursuit</i>, to overcome discretization error in the 1-dimensional case (e.g., spike-sorting). Here, we propose a more general algorithm that fits mixture models of any dimensionality without discretization. Our algorithm uses the principles of L2-boost [4], together with refitting of the weights and pruning of the parameters. The addition of these steps to L2-boost both accelerates the algorithm and assures its accuracy. We refer to the resulting algorithm as <i>elastic basis pursuit</i>, or EBP, since it expands and contracts the active set of kernels as needed. We show that in contrast to existing approaches to fitting mixtures, our boosting framework (1) enables the selection of the optimal bias-variance tradeoff along the solution path, and (2) scales with high-dimensional problems. In simulations of DWI, we find that EBP yields better parameter estimates than a non-negative least squares (NNLS) approach, or the standard model used in DWI, the tensor model, which serves as the basis for diffusion tensor imaging (DTI) [5]. We demonstrate the utility of the method in DWI data acquired in parts of the brain containing crossings of multiple fascicles of nerve fibers.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/25684972/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">25684972</a> | PMC:<a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/PMC4324561/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">PMC4324561</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">pubmed:25684972</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2015 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Charles Y Zheng</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Franco Pestilli</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Ariel Rokem</dc:creator>
      <dc:date>2015-02-17</dc:date>
      <dc:source>Advances in neural information processing systems</dc:source>
      <dc:title>Deconvolution of High Dimensional Mixtures via Boosting, with Application to Diffusion-Weighted MRI of Human Brain</dc:title>
      <dc:identifier>pmid:25684972</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>pmc:PMC4324561</dc:identifier>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Altered white matter in early visual pathways of humans with amblyopia</title>
      <link>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/25615840/?utm_source=Python Requests&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&amp;fc=20210112114804&amp;ff=20210323133437&amp;v=2.14.3</link>
      <description>Amblyopia is a visual disorder caused by poorly coordinated binocular input during development. Little is known about the impact of amblyopia on the white matter within the visual system. We studied the properties of six major visual white-matter pathways in a group of adults with amblyopia (n=10) and matched controls (n=10) using diffusion weighted imaging (DWI) and fiber tractography. While we did not find significant differences in diffusion properties in cortico-cortical pathways, patients...</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Vision Res. 2015 Sep;114:48-55. doi: 10.1016/j.visres.2014.12.021. Epub 2015 Jan 20.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Amblyopia is a visual disorder caused by poorly coordinated binocular input during development. Little is known about the impact of amblyopia on the white matter within the visual system. We studied the properties of six major visual white-matter pathways in a group of adults with amblyopia (n=10) and matched controls (n=10) using diffusion weighted imaging (DWI) and fiber tractography. While we did not find significant differences in diffusion properties in cortico-cortical pathways, patients with amblyopia exhibited increased mean diffusivity in thalamo-cortical visual pathways. These findings suggest that amblyopia may systematically alter the white matter properties of early visual pathways. </p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/25615840/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">25615840</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.visres.2014.12.021>10.1016/j.visres.2014.12.021</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">pubmed:25615840</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2015 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Brian Allen</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Daniel P Spiegel</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Benjamin Thompson</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Franco Pestilli</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Bas Rokers</dc:creator>
      <dc:date>2015-01-24</dc:date>
      <dc:source>Vision research</dc:source>
      <dc:title>Altered white matter in early visual pathways of humans with amblyopia</dc:title>
      <dc:identifier>pmid:25615840</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.visres.2014.12.021</dc:identifier>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Functionally defined white matter reveals segregated pathways in human ventral temporal cortex associated with category-specific processing</title>
      <link>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/25569351/?utm_source=Python Requests&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&amp;fc=20210112114804&amp;ff=20210323133437&amp;v=2.14.3</link>
      <description>It is unknown if the white-matter properties associated with specific visual networks selectively affect category-specific processing. In a novel protocol we combined measurements of white-matter structure, functional selectivity, and behavior in the same subjects. We find two parallel white-matter pathways along the ventral temporal lobe connecting to either face-selective or place-selective regions. Diffusion properties of portions of these tracts adjacent to face- and place-selective regions...</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Neuron. 2015 Jan 7;85(1):216-227. doi: 10.1016/j.neuron.2014.12.027.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">It is unknown if the white-matter properties associated with specific visual networks selectively affect category-specific processing. In a novel protocol we combined measurements of white-matter structure, functional selectivity, and behavior in the same subjects. We find two parallel white-matter pathways along the ventral temporal lobe connecting to either face-selective or place-selective regions. Diffusion properties of portions of these tracts adjacent to face- and place-selective regions of ventral temporal cortex correlate with behavioral performance for face or place processing, respectively. Strikingly, adults with developmental prosopagnosia (face blindness) express an atypical structure-behavior relationship near face-selective cortex, suggesting that white-matter atypicalities in this region may have behavioral consequences. These data suggest that examining the interplay between cortical function, anatomical connectivity, and visual behavior is integral to understanding functional networks and their role in producing visual abilities and deficits.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/25569351/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">25569351</a> | PMC:<a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/PMC4287959/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">PMC4287959</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2014.12.027>10.1016/j.neuron.2014.12.027</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">pubmed:25569351</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2015 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Jesse Gomez</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Franco Pestilli</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Nathan Witthoft</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Golijeh Golarai</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Alina Liberman</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Sonia Poltoratski</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Jennifer Yoon</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Kalanit Grill-Spector</dc:creator>
      <dc:date>2015-01-09</dc:date>
      <dc:source>Neuron</dc:source>
      <dc:title>Functionally defined white matter reveals segregated pathways in human ventral temporal cortex associated with category-specific processing</dc:title>
      <dc:identifier>pmid:25569351</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>pmc:PMC4287959</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.neuron.2014.12.027</dc:identifier>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Saccade planning evokes topographically specific activity in the dorsal and ventral streams</title>
      <link>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/25568118/?utm_source=Python Requests&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&amp;fc=20210112114804&amp;ff=20210323133437&amp;v=2.14.3</link>
      <description>Saccade planning may invoke spatially-specific feedback signals that bias early visual activity in favor of top-down goals. We tested this hypothesis by measuring cortical activity at the early stages of the dorsal and ventral visual processing streams. Human subjects maintained saccade plans to (prosaccade) or away (antisaccade) from a spatial location over long memory-delays. Results show that cortical activity persists in early visual cortex at the retinotopic location of upcoming saccade...</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">J Neurosci. 2015 Jan 7;35(1):245-52. doi: 10.1523/JNEUROSCI.1687-14.2015.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Saccade planning may invoke spatially-specific feedback signals that bias early visual activity in favor of top-down goals. We tested this hypothesis by measuring cortical activity at the early stages of the dorsal and ventral visual processing streams. Human subjects maintained saccade plans to (prosaccade) or away (antisaccade) from a spatial location over long memory-delays. Results show that cortical activity persists in early visual cortex at the retinotopic location of upcoming saccade goals. Topographically specific activity persists as early as V1, and activity increases along both dorsal (V3A/B, IPS0) and ventral (hV4, VO1) visual areas. Importantly, activity persists when saccade goals are available only via working memory and when visual targets and saccade goals are spatially disassociated. We conclude that top-down signals elicit retinotopically specific activity in visual cortex both in the dorsal and ventral streams. Such activity may underlie mechanisms that prioritize locations of task-relevant objects. </p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/25568118/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">25568118</a> | PMC:<a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/PMC4287145/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">PMC4287145</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.1687-14.2015>10.1523/JNEUROSCI.1687-14.2015</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">pubmed:25568118</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2015 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Golbarg T Saber</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Franco Pestilli</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Clayton E Curtis</dc:creator>
      <dc:date>2015-01-09</dc:date>
      <dc:source>The Journal of neuroscience : the official journal of the Society for Neuroscience</dc:source>
      <dc:title>Saccade planning evokes topographically specific activity in the dorsal and ventral streams</dc:title>
      <dc:identifier>pmid:25568118</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>pmc:PMC4287145</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>doi:10.1523/JNEUROSCI.1687-14.2015</dc:identifier>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The vertical occipital fasciculus: a century of controversy resolved by in vivo measurements</title>
      <link>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/25404310/?utm_source=Python Requests&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&amp;fc=20210112114804&amp;ff=20210323133437&amp;v=2.14.3</link>
      <description>The vertical occipital fasciculus (VOF) is the only major fiber bundle connecting dorsolateral and ventrolateral visual cortex. Only a handful of studies have examined the anatomy of the VOF or its role in cognition in the living human brain. Here, we trace the contentious history of the VOF, beginning with its original discovery in monkey by Wernicke (1881) and in human by Obersteiner (1888), to its disappearance from the literature, and recent reemergence a century later. We introduce an...</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2014 Dec 2;111(48):E5214-23. doi: 10.1073/pnas.1418503111. Epub 2014 Nov 17.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">The vertical occipital fasciculus (VOF) is the only major fiber bundle connecting dorsolateral and ventrolateral visual cortex. Only a handful of studies have examined the anatomy of the VOF or its role in cognition in the living human brain. Here, we trace the contentious history of the VOF, beginning with its original discovery in monkey by Wernicke (1881) and in human by Obersteiner (1888), to its disappearance from the literature, and recent reemergence a century later. We introduce an algorithm to identify the VOF in vivo using diffusion-weighted imaging and tractography, and show that the VOF can be found in every hemisphere (n = 74). Quantitative T1 measurements demonstrate that tissue properties, such as myelination, in the VOF differ from neighboring white-matter tracts. The terminations of the VOF are in consistent positions relative to cortical folding patterns in the dorsal and ventral visual streams. Recent findings demonstrate that these same anatomical locations also mark cytoarchitectonic and functional transitions in dorsal and ventral visual cortex. We conclude that the VOF is likely to serve a unique role in the communication of signals between regions on the ventral surface that are important for the perception of visual categories (e.g., words, faces, bodies, etc.) and regions on the dorsal surface involved in the control of eye movements, attention, and motion perception. </p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/25404310/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">25404310</a> | PMC:<a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/PMC4260539/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">PMC4260539</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1418503111>10.1073/pnas.1418503111</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">pubmed:25404310</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2014 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Jason D Yeatman</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Kevin S Weiner</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Franco Pestilli</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Ariel Rokem</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Aviv Mezer</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Brian A Wandell</dc:creator>
      <dc:date>2014-11-19</dc:date>
      <dc:source>Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America</dc:source>
      <dc:title>The vertical occipital fasciculus: a century of controversy resolved by in vivo measurements</dc:title>
      <dc:identifier>pmid:25404310</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>pmc:PMC4260539</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>doi:10.1073/pnas.1418503111</dc:identifier>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Speed discrimination predicts word but not pseudo-word reading rate in adults and children</title>
      <link>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/25278418/?utm_source=Python Requests&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&amp;fc=20210112114804&amp;ff=20210323133437&amp;v=2.14.3</link>
      <description>Visual processing in the magnocellular pathway is a reputed influence on word recognition and reading performance. However, the mechanisms behind this relationship are still unclear. To explore this concept, we measured reading rate, speed-discrimination, and contrast detection thresholds in adults and children with a wide range of reading abilities. We found that speed discrimination thresholds are higher in children than in adults and are correlated with age. Speed discrimination thresholds...</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Brain Lang. 2014 Nov;138:27-37. doi: 10.1016/j.bandl.2014.09.003. Epub 2014 Sep 29.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Visual processing in the magnocellular pathway is a reputed influence on word recognition and reading performance. However, the mechanisms behind this relationship are still unclear. To explore this concept, we measured reading rate, speed-discrimination, and contrast detection thresholds in adults and children with a wide range of reading abilities. We found that speed discrimination thresholds are higher in children than in adults and are correlated with age. Speed discrimination thresholds are also correlated with reading rates but only for real words, not pseudo-words. Conversely, we found no correlations between contrast detection thresholds and the reading rates. We also found no correlations between speed discrimination or contrast detection and WASI subtest scores. These findings indicate that familiarity is a factor in magnocellular operations that may influence reading rate. We suggest this effect supports the idea that the magnocellular pathway contributes to word reading through an analysis of letter position. </p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/25278418/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">25278418</a> | PMC:<a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/PMC4300234/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">PMC4300234</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bandl.2014.09.003>10.1016/j.bandl.2014.09.003</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">pubmed:25278418</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2014 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Keith L Main</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Franco Pestilli</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Aviv Mezer</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Jason Yeatman</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Ryan Martin</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Stephanie Phipps</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Brian Wandell</dc:creator>
      <dc:date>2014-10-04</dc:date>
      <dc:source>Brain and language</dc:source>
      <dc:title>Speed discrimination predicts word but not pseudo-word reading rate in adults and children</dc:title>
      <dc:identifier>pmid:25278418</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>pmc:PMC4300234</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.bandl.2014.09.003</dc:identifier>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>White matter consequences of retinal receptor and ganglion cell damage</title>
      <link>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/25257055/?utm_source=Python Requests&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&amp;fc=20210112114804&amp;ff=20210323133437&amp;v=2.14.3</link>
      <description>CONCLUSIONS: Both photoreceptor layer (CRD) and retinal ganglion cell (LHON) retinal disease causes substantial change in the visual white matter. These changes can be measured using diffusion MRI. The diffusion changes measured in the optic tract and the optic radiation differ, suggesting that they are caused by different biological mechanisms.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Invest Ophthalmol Vis Sci. 2014 Sep 25;55(10):6976-86. doi: 10.1167/iovs.14-14737.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">PURPOSE: Patients with Leber hereditary optic neuropathy (LHON) and cone-rod dystrophy (CRD) have central vision loss; but CRD damages the retinal photoreceptor layer, and LHON damages the retinal ganglion cell (RGC) layer. Using diffusion MRI, we measured how these two types of retinal damage affect the optic tract (ganglion cell axons) and optic radiation (geniculo-striate axons).</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">METHODS: Adult onset CRD (n = 5), LHON (n = 6), and healthy controls (n = 14) participated in the study. We used probabilistic fiber tractography to identify the optic tract and the optic radiation. We compared axial and radial diffusivity at many positions along the optic tract and the optic radiation.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">RESULTS: In both types of patients, diffusion measures within the optic tract and the optic radiation differ from controls. The optic tract change is principally a decrease in axial diffusivity; the optic radiation change is principally an increase in radial diffusivity.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">CONCLUSIONS: Both photoreceptor layer (CRD) and retinal ganglion cell (LHON) retinal disease causes substantial change in the visual white matter. These changes can be measured using diffusion MRI. The diffusion changes measured in the optic tract and the optic radiation differ, suggesting that they are caused by different biological mechanisms.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/25257055/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">25257055</a> | PMC:<a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/PMC4215745/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">PMC4215745</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1167/iovs.14-14737>10.1167/iovs.14-14737</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">pubmed:25257055</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2014 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Shumpei Ogawa</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Hiromasa Takemura</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Hiroshi Horiguchi</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Masahiko Terao</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Tomoki Haji</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Franco Pestilli</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Jason D Yeatman</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Hiroshi Tsuneoka</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Brian A Wandell</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Yoichiro Masuda</dc:creator>
      <dc:date>2014-09-27</dc:date>
      <dc:source>Investigative ophthalmology &amp; visual science</dc:source>
      <dc:title>White matter consequences of retinal receptor and ganglion cell damage</dc:title>
      <dc:identifier>pmid:25257055</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>pmc:PMC4215745</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>doi:10.1167/iovs.14-14737</dc:identifier>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluation and statistical inference for human connectomes</title>
      <link>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/25194848/?utm_source=Python Requests&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&amp;fc=20210112114804&amp;ff=20210323133437&amp;v=2.14.3</link>
      <description>Diffusion-weighted imaging coupled with tractography is currently the only method for in vivo mapping of human white-matter fascicles. Tractography takes diffusion measurements as input and produces the connectome, a large collection of white-matter fascicles, as output. We introduce a method to evaluate the evidence supporting connectomes. Linear fascicle evaluation (LiFE) takes any connectome as input and predicts diffusion measurements as output, using the difference between the measured and...</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Nat Methods. 2014 Oct;11(10):1058-63. doi: 10.1038/nmeth.3098. Epub 2014 Sep 7.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Diffusion-weighted imaging coupled with tractography is currently the only method for in vivo mapping of human white-matter fascicles. Tractography takes diffusion measurements as input and produces the connectome, a large collection of white-matter fascicles, as output. We introduce a method to evaluate the evidence supporting connectomes. Linear fascicle evaluation (LiFE) takes any connectome as input and predicts diffusion measurements as output, using the difference between the measured and predicted diffusion signals to quantify the prediction error. We use the prediction error to evaluate the evidence that supports the properties of the connectome, to compare tractography algorithms and to test hypotheses about tracts and connections. </p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/25194848/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">25194848</a> | PMC:<a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/PMC4180802/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">PMC4180802</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1038/nmeth.3098>10.1038/nmeth.3098</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">pubmed:25194848</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2014 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Franco Pestilli</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Jason D Yeatman</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Ariel Rokem</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Kendrick N Kay</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Brian A Wandell</dc:creator>
      <dc:date>2014-09-08</dc:date>
      <dc:source>Nature methods</dc:source>
      <dc:title>Evaluation and statistical inference for human connectomes</dc:title>
      <dc:identifier>pmid:25194848</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>pmc:PMC4180802</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>doi:10.1038/nmeth.3098</dc:identifier>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A review of the mechanisms by which attentional feedback shapes visual selectivity</title>
      <link>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/24990408/?utm_source=Python Requests&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&amp;fc=20210112114804&amp;ff=20210323133437&amp;v=2.14.3</link>
      <description>The glut of information available for the brain to process at any given moment necessitates an efficient attentional system that can 'pick and choose' what information receives prioritized processing. A growing body of work, spanning numerous methodologies and species, reveals that one powerful way in which attending to an item separates the wheat from the chaff is by altering a basic response property in the brain: neuronal selectivity. Selectivity is a cornerstone response property, largely...</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Brain Struct Funct. 2015;220(3):1237-50. doi: 10.1007/s00429-014-0818-5. Epub 2014 Jul 3.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">The glut of information available for the brain to process at any given moment necessitates an efficient attentional system that can 'pick and choose' what information receives prioritized processing. A growing body of work, spanning numerous methodologies and species, reveals that one powerful way in which attending to an item separates the wheat from the chaff is by altering a basic response property in the brain: neuronal selectivity. Selectivity is a cornerstone response property, largely dictating our ability to represent and interact with the environment. Although it is likely that selectivity is altered throughout many brain areas, here we focus on how directing attention to an item affects selectivity in the visual system, where this response property is generally more well characterized. First, we review the neural architecture supporting selectivity, and then discuss the various changes that could occur in selectivity for an attended item. In a survey of the literature, spanning neurophysiology, neuroimaging and psychophysics, we reveal that there is general convergence regarding the manner with which selectivity is shaped by attentional feedback. In a nutshell, the literature suggests that the type of changes in selectivity that manifest appears to depend on the type of attention being deployed: whereas directing spatial attention towards an item only alters spatial selectivity, directing feature-based attention can alter the selectivity of attended features. </p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/24990408/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">24990408</a> | PMC:<a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/PMC4282837/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">PMC4282837</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1007/s00429-014-0818-5>10.1007/s00429-014-0818-5</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">pubmed:24990408</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2014 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Sam Ling</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Janneke F M Jehee</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Franco Pestilli</dc:creator>
      <dc:date>2014-07-04</dc:date>
      <dc:source>Brain structure &amp; function</dc:source>
      <dc:title>A review of the mechanisms by which attentional feedback shapes visual selectivity</dc:title>
      <dc:identifier>pmid:24990408</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>pmc:PMC4282837</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>doi:10.1007/s00429-014-0818-5</dc:identifier>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Differing effects of attention in single-units and populations are well predicted by heterogeneous tuning and the normalization model of attention</title>
      <link>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/24600380/?utm_source=Python Requests&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&amp;fc=20210112114804&amp;ff=20210323133437&amp;v=2.14.3</link>
      <description>Single-unit measurements have reported many different effects of attention on contrast-response (e.g., contrast-gain, response-gain, additive-offset dependent on visibility), while functional imaging measurements have more uniformly reported increases in response across all contrasts (additive-offset). The normalization model of attention elegantly predicts the diversity of effects of attention reported in single-units well-tuned to the stimulus, but what predictions does it make for more...</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Front Comput Neurosci. 2014 Feb 19;8:12. doi: 10.3389/fncom.2014.00012. eCollection 2014.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Single-unit measurements have reported many different effects of attention on contrast-response (e.g., contrast-gain, response-gain, additive-offset dependent on visibility), while functional imaging measurements have more uniformly reported increases in response across all contrasts (additive-offset). The normalization model of attention elegantly predicts the diversity of effects of attention reported in single-units well-tuned to the stimulus, but what predictions does it make for more realistic populations of neurons with heterogeneous tuning? Are predictions in accordance with population-scale measurements? We used functional imaging data from humans to determine a realistic ratio of attention-field to stimulus-drive size (a key parameter for the model) and predicted effects of attention in a population of model neurons with heterogeneous tuning. We found that within the population, neurons well-tuned to the stimulus showed a response-gain effect, while less-well-tuned neurons showed a contrast-gain effect. Averaged across the population, these disparate effects of attention gave rise to additive-offsets in contrast-response, similar to reports in human functional imaging as well as population averages of single-units. Differences in predictions for single-units and populations were observed across a wide range of model parameters (ratios of attention-field to stimulus-drive size and the amount of baseline response modifiable by attention), offering an explanation for disparity in physiological reports. Thus, by accounting for heterogeneity in tuning of realistic neuronal populations, the normalization model of attention can not only predict responses of well-tuned neurons, but also the activity of large populations of neurons. More generally, computational models can unify physiological findings across different scales of measurement, and make links to behavior, but only if factors such as heterogeneous tuning within a population are properly accounted for. </p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/24600380/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">24600380</a> | PMC:<a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/PMC3928538/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">PMC3928538</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.3389/fncom.2014.00012>10.3389/fncom.2014.00012</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">pubmed:24600380</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2014 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Yuko Hara</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Franco Pestilli</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Justin L Gardner</dc:creator>
      <dc:date>2014-03-07</dc:date>
      <dc:source>Frontiers in computational neuroscience</dc:source>
      <dc:title>Differing effects of attention in single-units and populations are well predicted by heterogeneous tuning and the normalization model of attention</dc:title>
      <dc:identifier>pmid:24600380</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>pmc:PMC3928538</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>doi:10.3389/fncom.2014.00012</dc:identifier>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Attentional enhancement via selection and pooling of early sensory responses in human visual cortex</title>
      <link>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/22153378/?utm_source=Python Requests&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&amp;fc=20210112114804&amp;ff=20210323133437&amp;v=2.14.3</link>
      <description>The computational processes by which attention improves behavioral performance were characterized by measuring visual cortical activity with functional magnetic resonance imaging as humans performed a contrast-discrimination task with focal and distributed attention. Focal attention yielded robust improvements in behavioral performance accompanied by increases in cortical responses. Quantitative analysis revealed that if performance were limited only by the sensitivity of the measured sensory...</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Neuron. 2011 Dec 8;72(5):832-46. doi: 10.1016/j.neuron.2011.09.025.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">The computational processes by which attention improves behavioral performance were characterized by measuring visual cortical activity with functional magnetic resonance imaging as humans performed a contrast-discrimination task with focal and distributed attention. Focal attention yielded robust improvements in behavioral performance accompanied by increases in cortical responses. Quantitative analysis revealed that if performance were limited only by the sensitivity of the measured sensory signals, the improvements in behavioral performance would have corresponded to an unrealistically large reduction in response variability. Instead, behavioral performance was well characterized by a pooling and selection process for which the largest sensory responses, those most strongly modulated by attention, dominated the perceptual decision. This characterization predicts that high-contrast distracters that evoke large responses should negatively impact behavioral performance. We tested and confirmed this prediction. We conclude that attention enhanced behavioral performance predominantly by enabling efficient selection of the behaviorally relevant sensory signals.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/22153378/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">22153378</a> | PMC:<a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/PMC3264681/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">PMC3264681</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2011.09.025>10.1016/j.neuron.2011.09.025</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">pubmed:22153378</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2011 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Franco Pestilli</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Marisa Carrasco</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>David J Heeger</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Justin L Gardner</dc:creator>
      <dc:date>2011-12-14</dc:date>
      <dc:source>Neuron</dc:source>
      <dc:title>Attentional enhancement via selection and pooling of early sensory responses in human visual cortex</dc:title>
      <dc:identifier>pmid:22153378</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>pmc:PMC3264681</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.neuron.2011.09.025</dc:identifier>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Attention trades off spatial acuity</title>
      <link>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/19385088/?utm_source=Python Requests&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&amp;fc=20210112114804&amp;ff=20210323133437&amp;v=2.14.3</link>
      <description>Covertly attending to a stimulus location increases spatial acuity. Is such increased spatial acuity coupled with a decreased acuity at unattended locations? We measured the effects of exogenous (transient and involuntary) and endogenous (sustained and voluntary) attention on observers' acuity thresholds for a Landolt gap resolution task at both attended and unattended locations. Both types of attention increased acuity at the attended and decreased it at unattended locations relative to a...</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Vision Res. 2009 Mar;49(7):735-45. doi: 10.1016/j.visres.2009.02.001.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Covertly attending to a stimulus location increases spatial acuity. Is such increased spatial acuity coupled with a decreased acuity at unattended locations? We measured the effects of exogenous (transient and involuntary) and endogenous (sustained and voluntary) attention on observers' acuity thresholds for a Landolt gap resolution task at both attended and unattended locations. Both types of attention increased acuity at the attended and decreased it at unattended locations relative to a neutral baseline condition. These trade-off findings support the idea that limited processing resources affect early vision, even when the display is impoverished and there is no location uncertainty. There was no benefit without a cost.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/19385088/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">19385088</a> | PMC:<a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/PMC3375052/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">PMC3375052</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.visres.2009.02.001>10.1016/j.visres.2009.02.001</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">pubmed:19385088</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2009 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Barbara Montagna</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Franco Pestilli</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Marisa Carrasco</dc:creator>
      <dc:date>2009-04-23</dc:date>
      <dc:source>Vision research</dc:source>
      <dc:title>Attention trades off spatial acuity</dc:title>
      <dc:identifier>pmid:19385088</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>pmc:PMC3375052</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.visres.2009.02.001</dc:identifier>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Functional imaging with reinforcement, eyetracking, and physiological monitoring</title>
      <link>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/19066528/?utm_source=Python Requests&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&amp;fc=20210112114804&amp;ff=20210323133437&amp;v=2.14.3</link>
      <description>We use functional brain imaging (fMRI) to study neural circuits that underlie decision-making. To understand how outcomes affect decision processes, simple perceptual tasks are combined with appetitive and aversive reinforcement. However, the use of reinforcers such as juice and airpuffs can create challenges for fMRI. Reinforcer delivery can cause head movement, which creates artifacts in the fMRI signal. Reinforcement can also lead to changes in heart rate and respiration that are mediated by...</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">J Vis Exp. 2008 Nov 13;(21):992. doi: 10.3791/992.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">We use functional brain imaging (fMRI) to study neural circuits that underlie decision-making. To understand how outcomes affect decision processes, simple perceptual tasks are combined with appetitive and aversive reinforcement. However, the use of reinforcers such as juice and airpuffs can create challenges for fMRI. Reinforcer delivery can cause head movement, which creates artifacts in the fMRI signal. Reinforcement can also lead to changes in heart rate and respiration that are mediated by autonomic pathways. Changes in heart rate and respiration can directly affect the fMRI (BOLD) signal in the brain and can be confounded with signal changes that are due to neural activity. In this presentation, we demonstrate methods for administering reinforcers in a controlled manner, for stabilizing the head, and for measuring pulse and respiration.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/19066528/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">19066528</a> | PMC:<a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/PMC2731772/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">PMC2731772</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.3791/992>10.3791/992</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">pubmed:19066528</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2008 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Vincent Ferrera</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Jack Grinband</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Tobias Teichert</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Franco Pestilli</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Stephen Dashnaw</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Joy Hirsch</dc:creator>
      <dc:date>2008-12-11</dc:date>
      <dc:source>Journal of visualized experiments : JoVE</dc:source>
      <dc:title>Functional imaging with reinforcement, eyetracking, and physiological monitoring</dc:title>
      <dc:identifier>pmid:19066528</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>pmc:PMC2731772</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>doi:10.3791/992</dc:identifier>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A population-coding model of attention's influence on contrast response: Estimating neural effects from psychophysical data</title>
      <link>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/18926845/?utm_source=Python Requests&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&amp;fc=20210112114804&amp;ff=20210323133437&amp;v=2.14.3</link>
      <description>Human psychophysics and monkey physiology studies have shown that attention modulates early vision - contrast sensitivity and processing. But how can we bridge the effects of attention on perceptual performance to their neural underpinnings? Here we implement a population-coding model that estimates attentional effects on population contrast response given psychophysical data. Model results show that whereas endogenous (sustained, voluntary) attention changes population contrast-response via...</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Vision Res. 2009 Jun;49(10):1144-53. doi: 10.1016/j.visres.2008.09.018. Epub 2008 Nov 7.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Human psychophysics and monkey physiology studies have shown that attention modulates early vision - contrast sensitivity and processing. But how can we bridge the effects of attention on perceptual performance to their neural underpinnings? Here we implement a population-coding model that estimates attentional effects on population contrast response given psychophysical data. Model results show that whereas endogenous (sustained, voluntary) attention changes population contrast-response via contrast gain, exogenous (transient, involuntary) attention changes population contrast-response via response gain.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/18926845/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">18926845</a> | PMC:<a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/PMC2743869/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">PMC2743869</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.visres.2008.09.018>10.1016/j.visres.2008.09.018</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">pubmed:18926845</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2008 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Franco Pestilli</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Sam Ling</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Marisa Carrasco</dc:creator>
      <dc:date>2008-10-18</dc:date>
      <dc:source>Vision research</dc:source>
      <dc:title>A population-coding model of attention's influence on contrast response: Estimating neural effects from psychophysical data</dc:title>
      <dc:identifier>pmid:18926845</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>pmc:PMC2743869</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.visres.2008.09.018</dc:identifier>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How do attention and adaptation affect contrast sensitivity?</title>
      <link>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/17685805/?utm_source=Python Requests&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&amp;fc=20210112114804&amp;ff=20210323133437&amp;v=2.14.3</link>
      <description>Attention and adaptation are both mechanisms that optimize visual performance. Attention optimizes performance by increasing contrast sensitivity for and neural response to attended stimuli while decreasing them for unattended stimuli; adaptation optimizes performance by increasing contrast sensitivity for and neural response to changing stimuli while decreasing them for unchanging stimuli. We investigated whether and how the adaptation state and the attentional effect on contrast sensitivity...</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">J Vis. 2007 May 30;7(7):9.1-12. doi: 10.1167/7.7.9.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Attention and adaptation are both mechanisms that optimize visual performance. Attention optimizes performance by increasing contrast sensitivity for and neural response to attended stimuli while decreasing them for unattended stimuli; adaptation optimizes performance by increasing contrast sensitivity for and neural response to changing stimuli while decreasing them for unchanging stimuli. We investigated whether and how the adaptation state and the attentional effect on contrast sensitivity interact. We measured contrast sensitivity with an orientation-discrimination task, in two adaptation conditions--adapt to 0% or 100% contrast--in focused, distributed, and withdrawn attentional conditions. We used threshold and asymptotic performance to index the magnitude of the attentional effect--enhancement or impairment in contrast sensitivity--before and after adapting to high-contrast stimuli. The results show that attention and adaptation affect the contrast psychometric function in a similar but opposite way: Attention increases stimulus salience, whereas adaptation reduces stimulus salience. An interesting finding is that the adaptation state does not modulate the magnitude of the attentional effect. This suggests that attention affects the normalized signal once the effect of contrast adaptation has taken place and that these two mechanisms act separately to change contrast sensitivity. Attention can overcome adaptation to restore contrast sensitivity.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/17685805/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">17685805</a> | PMC:<a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/PMC2633480/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">PMC2633480</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1167/7.7.9>10.1167/7.7.9</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">pubmed:17685805</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2007 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Franco Pestilli</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Gerardo Viera</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Marisa Carrasco</dc:creator>
      <dc:date>2007-08-10</dc:date>
      <dc:source>Journal of vision</dc:source>
      <dc:title>How do attention and adaptation affect contrast sensitivity?</dc:title>
      <dc:identifier>pmid:17685805</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>pmc:PMC2633480</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>doi:10.1167/7.7.9</dc:identifier>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Attention enhances contrast sensitivity at cued and impairs it at uncued locations</title>
      <link>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/15797776/?utm_source=Python Requests&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&amp;fc=20210112114804&amp;ff=20210323133437&amp;v=2.14.3</link>
      <description>Transient covert attention increases contrast sensitivity at the target location with an informative spatial cue. Here we explored whether an uninformative spatial cue (50% valid with two possible locations) also increases contrast sensitivity and whether contrast sensitivity is altered at the uncued location as compared to the neutral condition. For all four observers, transient covert attention had both a benefit and a cost: it enhanced contrast sensitivity at the cued location and impaired...</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Vision Res. 2005 Jun;45(14):1867-75. doi: 10.1016/j.visres.2005.01.019.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Transient covert attention increases contrast sensitivity at the target location with an informative spatial cue. Here we explored whether an uninformative spatial cue (50% valid with two possible locations) also increases contrast sensitivity and whether contrast sensitivity is altered at the uncued location as compared to the neutral condition. For all four observers, transient covert attention had both a benefit and a cost: it enhanced contrast sensitivity at the cued location and impaired contrast sensitivity at the uncued location at both parafoveal and peripheral positions. These results are consistent with the idea of limited resources, and indicate that transient attention helps control the expenditure of cortical computation.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/15797776/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">15797776</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.visres.2005.01.019>10.1016/j.visres.2005.01.019</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">pubmed:15797776</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2005 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Franco Pestilli</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Marisa Carrasco</dc:creator>
      <dc:date>2005-03-31</dc:date>
      <dc:source>Vision research</dc:source>
      <dc:title>Attention enhances contrast sensitivity at cued and impairs it at uncued locations</dc:title>
      <dc:identifier>pmid:15797776</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.visres.2005.01.019</dc:identifier>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transient attention enhances perceptual performance and FMRI response in human visual cortex</title>
      <link>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/15694332/?utm_source=Python Requests&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&amp;fc=20210112114804&amp;ff=20210323133437&amp;v=2.14.3</link>
      <description>When a visual stimulus suddenly appears, it captures attention, producing a transient improvement of performance on basic visual tasks. We investigate the effect of transient attention on stimulus representations in early visual areas using rapid event-related fMRI. Participants discriminated the orientation of one of two gratings preceded or followed by a nonpredictive peripheral cue. Compared to control conditions, precueing the target location improved performance and produced a larger fMRI...</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Neuron. 2005 Feb 3;45(3):469-77. doi: 10.1016/j.neuron.2004.12.039.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">When a visual stimulus suddenly appears, it captures attention, producing a transient improvement of performance on basic visual tasks. We investigate the effect of transient attention on stimulus representations in early visual areas using rapid event-related fMRI. Participants discriminated the orientation of one of two gratings preceded or followed by a nonpredictive peripheral cue. Compared to control conditions, precueing the target location improved performance and produced a larger fMRI response in corresponding retinotopic areas. This enhancement progressively increased from striate to extrastriate areas. Control conditions indicated that the enhanced fMRI response was not due to sensory summation of cue and target signals. Thus, an uninformative precue increases both perceptual performance and the concomitant stimulus-evoked activity in early visual areas. These results provide evidence regarding the retinotopically specific neural correlate for the effects of transient attention on early vision.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/15694332/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">15694332</a> | PMC:<a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/PMC3825510/?utm_source=Python Requests&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1-E-T-Pur1FBkVKbU8LjWt1-9Q259xhHJ9EYoUamU1xlaplMjx&fc=20210112114804&ff=20210323133437&v=2.14.3">PMC3825510</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2004.12.039>10.1016/j.neuron.2004.12.039</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">pubmed:15694332</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2005 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Taosheng Liu</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Franco Pestilli</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Marisa Carrasco</dc:creator>
      <dc:date>2005-02-08</dc:date>
      <dc:source>Neuron</dc:source>
      <dc:title>Transient attention enhances perceptual performance and FMRI response in human visual cortex</dc:title>
      <dc:identifier>pmid:15694332</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>pmc:PMC3825510</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.neuron.2004.12.039</dc:identifier>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
