<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>feature on Pestilli Lab</title><link>https://PESTILLILAB.github.io/tags/feature/</link><description>Recent content in feature on Pestilli Lab</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://PESTILLILAB.github.io/tags/feature/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Video Heading</title><link>https://PESTILLILAB.github.io/home/featurevideo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://PESTILLILAB.github.io/home/featurevideo/</guid><description>The PESTILLI LAB promotes progress in psychological and brain science via the democratization of scientific research, methods, data and infrastructure. We strive to advance societal good by accelerating neuroscientific discovery and education via data-science applications and innovative technology.</description></item><item><title>Vision statement</title><link>https://PESTILLILAB.github.io/home/feature/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://PESTILLILAB.github.io/home/feature/</guid><description>The PESTILLI LAB promotes progress in psychological and brain science via the democratization of scientific research, methods, data and infrastructure. We strive to advance societal good by accelerating neuroscientific discovery and education via data-science applications and innovative technology.</description></item><item><title>DATA NEUROSCIENCE and MACHINE LEARNING</title><link>https://PESTILLILAB.github.io/research/feature_dataneuro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://PESTILLILAB.github.io/research/feature_dataneuro/</guid><description>It has been claimed that data is the new oil. Today, a great potential for impact and a variety of applications exist for psychological science outside the traditional domain. Data about human behavior is collected routinely on cloud platforms around the nation, often for commerce sometimes for good other times for less clear purposes. Indeed, a majority of what is commonly referred to as Data Science can be specified as Psychological Data Science.</description></item><item><title>Diversity</title><link>https://PESTILLILAB.github.io/team/feature_diversity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://PESTILLILAB.github.io/team/feature_diversity/</guid><description>We believe that a good lab can only flourish if it embraces the ideas and backgrounds of a truly diverse set of talented people — of every background, race, ethnicity and life experience. We like to joke that our work has Italian design, Japanese technology and is made in America. Our PI is originally from Italy and we have a software engineer from Japan, but the rest of our lab is a diverse group of scientists as well.</description></item><item><title>Inclusivity</title><link>https://PESTILLILAB.github.io/team/feature_inclusivity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://PESTILLILAB.github.io/team/feature_inclusivity/</guid><description>We are committed to make educational and computational resources available to everyone that is interested in neuroscience, including communities that would otherwise not have access to these resources. Using data, analyses, and tutorials available on brainlife.io, we can teach neuroscience at institutions that do not have a neuroscience program. For instance, our brainlife.io team is developing a project in collaboration with Lawrence Technological University (LTU) to connect minority-serving institutions with neuroscience data and advanced computing resources.</description></item><item><title>OPEN NEUROSCIENCE and CLOUD TECHNOLOGY</title><link>https://PESTILLILAB.github.io/research/feature_openneuro_cloud/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://PESTILLILAB.github.io/research/feature_openneuro_cloud/</guid><description>We promote the application of cloud technology to psychological and brain science research. Why use cloud technology in neuroscience? “Isn’t that just for games or business?” Companies like Apple, Microsoft, Google, FaceBook and Amazon among thousands have benefited tremendously by developing products that use cloud services. A cloud service is software that runs for you via a remote computer. Software that does not sit inside a lab in an office building.</description></item><item><title>VISUAL WHITE MATTER and BRAIN NETWORKS</title><link>https://PESTILLILAB.github.io/research/feature_visualwhitematter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://PESTILLILAB.github.io/research/feature_visualwhitematter/</guid><description>Most humans use vision to explore the world. Clarifying how vision works is critical to understanding the brain and making progress towards disease prevention and cure. Visual function requires coordinating the activity of multiple components; the eye, cortical and subcortical brain regions. In the brain, visual signals travel across long-range myelinated axonal pathways that form an extensive network of neurons and brain areas. This myelinated network of neurons and axons is generally referred to as the ‘white matter.</description></item></channel></rss>