<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>feature on Pestilli Lab</title><link>https://PESTILLILAB.github.io/tags/feature/</link><description>Recent content in feature on Pestilli Lab</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://PESTILLILAB.github.io/tags/feature/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Humans, Science and Technology</title><link>https://PESTILLILAB.github.io/home/featurevideo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://PESTILLILAB.github.io/home/featurevideo/</guid><description>The PESTILLI LAB promotes progress in psychological and brain science via the democratization of scientific research, methods, data and infrastructure. We strive to advance societal good by accelerating neuroscientific discovery and education via data-science applications and innovative technology.</description></item><item><title>Vision statement</title><link>https://PESTILLILAB.github.io/home/feature/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://PESTILLILAB.github.io/home/feature/</guid><description>The PESTILLI LAB promotes progress in psychological and brain science via the democratization of scientific research, methods, data and infrastructure. We strive to advance societal good by accelerating neuroscientific discovery and education via data-science applications and innovative technology.</description></item><item><title>DATA NEUROSCIENCE and MACHINE LEARNING</title><link>https://PESTILLILAB.github.io/research/feature_dataneuro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://PESTILLILAB.github.io/research/feature_dataneuro/</guid><description>It has been claimed that data is the new oil. Discovery and understanding in psychological and brain science depend on the ability to process large amounts of &amp;ldquo;good data&amp;rdquo; to extract meaningful insights. The PESTILLI LAB capitalizes on the recent opportunities for large-scale data analysis, data science and machine learning. The lab uses advanced data-driven methods to find unexplored associations between brain biomarkers and behavior, and to advance scientific theory and understanding.</description></item><item><title>Diversity</title><link>https://PESTILLILAB.github.io/team/feature_diversity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://PESTILLILAB.github.io/team/feature_diversity/</guid><description>We believe that a good lab can only flourish if it embraces the ideas and backgrounds of a truly diverse set of talented people — of every background, race, ethnicity and life experience. We like to joke that our work has Italian design, Japanese technology and is made in America. Our PI is originally from Italy and we have a software engineer from Japan, but the rest of our lab is a diverse group of scientists as well.</description></item><item><title>Inclusivity</title><link>https://PESTILLILAB.github.io/team/feature_inclusivity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://PESTILLILAB.github.io/team/feature_inclusivity/</guid><description>We are committed to make educational and computational resources available to everyone that is interested in neuroscience, including communities that would otherwise not have access to these resources. Using data, analyses, and tutorials available on brainlife.io, we can teach neuroscience at institutions that do not have a neuroscience program. For instance, our brainlife.io team is developing a project in collaboration with Lawrence Technological University (LTU) to connect minority-serving institutions with neuroscience data and advanced computing resources.</description></item><item><title>OPEN NEUROSCIENCE and CLOUD TECHNOLOGY</title><link>https://PESTILLILAB.github.io/research/feature_openneuro_cloud/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://PESTILLILAB.github.io/research/feature_openneuro_cloud/</guid><description>We promote the application of cloud technology to support psychological and brain science science. Cloud technology can help scientists address bigger scientific questions and reduce mistakes. Cloud services allow error-less data analysis and management. The PESTILLI LAB has developed and operates brainlife.io, an open-source, free cloud computing platform that supports thousands of students and researchers with reproducible neuroimaging data processing.</description></item><item><title>VISUAL WHITE MATTER and BRAIN NETWORKS</title><link>https://PESTILLILAB.github.io/research/feature_visualwhitematter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://PESTILLILAB.github.io/research/feature_visualwhitematter/</guid><description>Vision is the primary human sense. Visual function requires coordinating the activity of multiple systems, from the eyes to the brain. Visual signals travel across long-range myelinated axonal pathways that form a network of neurons and brain areas. As of today, we understand much about the function of individual neurons and brain areas but less about communication between brain areas. The PESTILLI LAB works on understanding how neurons and brain areas connect and form networks and how these networks support human behavior.</description></item></channel></rss>